<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>74</id>
  <name>Heimerdinger</name>
  <displayName>Heimerdinger</displayName>
  <title>the Revered Inventor</title>
  <iconPath>Heimerdinger_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Heimerdinger_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>mage,pusher,ranged</tags>
  <description>It is unusual to see yordles outside of Bandle City, but the lure of science was something Heimerdinger could not resist. By the time he'd completed his third doctorate, he had already become the greatest of all yordle scientists and there was little his home could still offer him. The great academies of Piltover far to the north called to him, daring him to make his mark in the City of Progress. Knowing he would never thrive away from his own kind, Heimerdinger gathered like-minded yordles to join him in his quest, thus forming the backbone of the now famous Yordle Academy of Science &amp; Progress. Since then, he has become one of the most respected minds of the modern age and his academy is one of the leading institutions in all of Valoran. Heimerdinger has pioneered many new scientific achievements, delving deeper and deeper into the field of techmaturgy, including the development of the now ubiquitous star-rods that light many of the streets of the city-states. However, there is something strange about the Revered Inventor. In his quest to expand knowledge, he underwent an experiment of his own design to allow him to use a greater portion of his brain simultaneously. It most certainly worked, but at an unusual cost - Heimerdinger's brain increased in size. His head changed along with it and now the great scientist looks like a yordle with a giant brain-shaped head. Heimerdinger has turned his attentions to the current state of war on Valoran, however, and works to rectify what he considers is an unacceptable situation. Heimerdinger believes that science is the key to saving the world. Much more, he has rolled up his sleeves and is out to prove this as a member of the League of Legends - most definitely as the League's smartest champion! Science is on the march. Look out!</description>
  <quote />
  <quoteAuthor />
  <range>550</range>
  <moveSpeed>325</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>7</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>240</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>65</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.4</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.13</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.9</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.11</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>350</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>75</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>49.24</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>6</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>8</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>4</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>2</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Turret placement can be a deciding factor in a battle. Against most enemies placing pairs of turrets is the best method, but if they have a lot of area of effect abilities your turrets can be destroyed quickly.*Placing turrets in brush can lead to a surprise attack in your favor.*The blind component of Concussive Grenade is very important. It doesn't need to stun a target to be effective, so try hitting the ranged attackers in the back.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Work with the players in your lane to bring down Heimerdinger's turrets as soon as he brings them up. They become more effective if they are allowed to cluster.*Killing Heimerdinger will destroy his turrets. Try focusing him instead if his turrets get out of hand.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130216172601</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Techmaturgical Repair Bots</name>
      <iconPath>Heimerdinger_TechmaturgicalRepairBots.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Heimerdinger gives nearby allied Turrets and Champions increased Health Regeneration. </description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>H-28G Evolution Turret</name>
      <cost>70/80/90/100/110 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>1/1/1/1/1</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Heimerdinger_H28GEvolutionTurret.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Heimerdinger constructs a Machine Gun Turret with health and 30/38/46/54/62 (+0.2) magic damage (half damage to turrets). Max: 1/1/2/2/2 turret(s). Heimerdinger stores enough parts for a new turret every seconds. Each rank of this skill grants a further enhancement: Rank 2: Turret attacks reduce the target's armor and magic resist by 1 (max 50) Rank 3: Maximum turrets increased to 2 Rank 4: Turrets gain an additional 125 Health Rank 5: Turret attacks deal area damage</effect>
      <description>Heimerdinger lays down a machine gun turret. Turrets gain abilities as this skill is increased. (Turrets deal half damage to towers).</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Hextech Micro-Rockets</name>
      <cost>65/85/105/125/145 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/10/10/10/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Heimerdinger_HextechMicroRockets.png</iconPath>
      <range>1000</range>
      <effect>Heimerdinger fires 3 enemy seeking Micro-Rocket(s), hitting targets nearest to him. Each rocket deals 85/135/185/235/285 (+0.55) magic damage.</effect>
      <description>Heimerdinger fires long-range rockets that hit the enemies closest to Heimerdinger.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>CH-1 Concussion Grenade</name>
      <cost>80/90/100/110/120 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>13/12/11/10/9</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Heimerdinger_CH1ConcussionGrenade.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Heimerdinger tosses a grenade, dealing 80/135/190/245/300 (+0.6) magic damage to enemy units and blinding them for 1/1.5/2/2.5/3 seconds. Enemies who are directly hit are stunned for 1.5 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Heimerdinger lobs a grenade at a location, dealing damage to enemy units as well as stunning anyone directly hit and blinding surrounding units.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>UPGRADE!!!</name>
      <cost>90/90/90 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>120/105/90</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Heimerdinger_UPGRADE.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: 10/15/20% Cooldown Reduction. Active: All active Evolution Turrets are healed for 100% of their maximum health and also fire 20/25/30% movement-slowing frost shots. Additionally, your Hextech Micro-Rockets fire 5 rockets instead of 3 and your CH-1 Concussion Grenade travels faster.</effect>
      <description>Passive / Active: Passively increases Cooldown Reduction. Activate to heal all active Evolution Turrets and cause them to fire frost shots, which reduce Movement Speed, for a short time.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1005</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3028</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1005</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3028</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3157</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>