<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>91</id>
  <name>Talon</name>
  <displayName>Talon</displayName>
  <title>the Blade's Shadow</title>
  <iconPath>Talon_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Talon_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>assassin,melee</tags>
  <description>Talon's earliest memories are the darkness of Noxus' underground passages and the reassuring steel of a blade. He remembers no family, warmth, or kindness. Instead, the clink of stolen gold and the security of a wall at his back are all the kinship he has ever craved. Kept alive only by his quick wits and deft thievery, Talon scraped out a living in the seedy underbelly of Noxus. His mastery of the blade quickly marked him as a threat, and Noxian guilds sent assassins to him with a demand: join their ranks or be killed. He left the bodies of his pursuers dumped in Noxus' moat as his response. The assassination attempts grew increasingly dangerous until one assailant met Talon blade-for-blade in a match of strength. To his surprise, Talon was disarmed and facing down his executioner's sword when the assassin revealed himself to be General Du Couteau. The General offered Talon the choice between death at his hand, or life as an agent of the Noxian High Command. Talon chose life, on the condition that his service was to Du Couteau alone, for the only type of orders he could respect were from one he could not defeat. Talon remained in the shadows, carrying out secret missions on Du Couteau's orders that took him from the frigid lands of Freljord to the inner sanctums of Bandle City. When the general vanished, Talon considered reclaiming his freedom, but he had gained immense respect for Du Couteau after years in his service. He became obsessed with tracking down the general's whereabouts. Talon's suspicions led him to the doors of the Institute of War, where he joined the League of Legends in order to find those responsible for Du Couteau's disappearance.</description>
  <quote>The three deadliest blademasters in all of Valoran are bound to the house of Du Couteau: my father, myself, and Talon. Challenge us, if you dare.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Katarina Du Couteau</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>350</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>17</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>260</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>40</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.35</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.1</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.45</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.15</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>440</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>85</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>50</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.1</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>5</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>2</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>6</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>9</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Noxian Diplomacy naturally works well with Cutthroat. Try activating Noxian Diplomacy before leaping on your opponent with Cutthroat.*Shadow Assault is a powerful escape tool, but can also be offensively used to assault a group.*Remember to pick your target before the fight. Focusing all of Talon's abilities on one target can be very rewarding, but splitting them up between many may leave you helpless.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Talon's attacks are all physical damage. Build armor early to counter his burst damage.*Talon is heavily reliant on Shadow Assault to escape a fight. When it is down he's significantly more vulnerable.*Talon has no healing or sustain abilities. Weakening him in lane could force him to return to base.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Mercy</name>
      <iconPath>TalonMercy.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Talon deals 10% more damage with his basic attacks to any target that is slowed, stunned, immobilized, or suppressed.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Noxian Diplomacy</name>
      <cost>40/45/50/55/60 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>8/7/6/5/4</cooldown>
      <iconPath>TalonNoxianDiplomacy.png</iconPath>
      <range>300</range>
      <effect>Talon's next basic attack deals an additional 30/60/90/120/150 (+) physical damage. If the target is a champion, the target will bleed for 10/20/30/40/50 (+) physical damage over 6/6/6/6/6 seconds, revealing their location for the duration.</effect>
      <description>Talon's next basic attack deals bonus physical damage. If the target is a champion, they will bleed, taking additional physical damage over a period of time and revealing their location for the duration.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Rake</name>
      <cost>60/65/70/75/80 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/10/10/10/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>TalonRake.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Talon sends out a volley of daggers that then return back to him, dealing 30/55/80/105/130 (+) physical damage every time it passes through an enemy. Additionally the enemy is slowed by 20/25/30/35/40% for 2/2/2/2/2 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Talon sends out a volley of daggers that then return back to him, dealing physical damage every time it passes through an enemy. Additionally the enemy is slowed for a short duration.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Cutthroat</name>
      <cost>35/40/45/50/55 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>18/16/14/12/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>TalonCutthroat.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Talon instantly appears behind his target, silencing them for 1/1/1/1/1 second and amplifying Talon's damage against the target by 3/6/9/12/15% for 3/3/3/3/3 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Talon instantly appears behind his target, silencing them and amplifying his damage against that target.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Shadow Assault</name>
      <cost>80/90/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>75/65/55</cooldown>
      <iconPath>TalonShadowAssault.png</iconPath>
      <range>650</range>
      <effect>Talon disperses a ring of blades and becomes invisible for up to 2.5/2.5/2.5 seconds, gaining 40/40/40% Movement Speed. When Talon emerges from invisibility, the blades converge on his location. Every time a blade passes through an enemy, they receive 120/170/220 (+) physical damage. </effect>
      <description>Talon disperses a ring of blades and becomes invisible while gaining additional Movement Speed. When Talon emerges from invisibility, the blades converge on his location. Every time a blade passes through an enemy, they receive physical damage.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3134</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3072</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1062</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3117</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3134</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3180</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>