<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>78</id>
  <name>Poppy</name>
  <displayName>Poppy</displayName>
  <title>the Iron Ambassador</title>
  <iconPath>Poppy_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Poppy_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,assassin,melee</tags>
  <description>While other young yordle girls played skip-step and braided wreathes out of posies, Poppy spent her youth earning calluses and grease stains in her father's armor shop. Blomgrun, her father, was Bandle City's finest smith. The only thing he loved as much as his work was his young daughter, Poppy - named for the sprightly sounds of the sparks that leapt from his ever-burning forge. He welled with pride the day she was first able to lift his trusty hammer, Whomper. Poppy immediately took to his art, demonstrating a natural gift for smithing, which Blomgrun honed with devoted instruction. One day, a Demacian general named Florin Berell commissioned Blomgrun to craft a helm, glorious beyond comparison. Blomgrun toiled away on this project, determined to present Florin with his finest work. He let Poppy set the center jewel, entrusting her with the most important piece. When the pair finished, they departed for Demacia to deliver it in person. Word of the general's order, however, was leaked to the Noxian High Command, and two Noxian assassins were dispatched to intercept the delivery. Blomgrun was able to occupy the assassins long enough for Poppy to escape with the prized helm. She watched helplessly from the brush as her father was slain. Instead of fleeing home, she carried the helm the rest of the way to Demacia alone. She refused payment for it, saying that no amount would compensate for her father's life. Instead, she offered it as a gift, honoring her father's final intentions. Florin saw the grim determination behind the tears in her eyes, and requested that the leadership of Bandle City appoint Poppy as the yordle ambassador to Demacia. Soon after, seeking to crush Noxus with her father's hammer, Poppy volunteered for the League of Legends. Poppy may be small, but Whomper - or her will - is not.</description>
  <quote />
  <quoteAuthor />
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>345</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>18</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>4</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>185</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>30</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.28</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.09</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.49</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.11</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>423</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>81</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>56.3</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.375</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>5</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>8</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>6</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>4</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Diplomatic Immunity can be used both defensively and offensively. It can be valuable to select a high damage target and try to kill them.*Try using Paragon of Demacia's movement speed burst to position your Heroic Charge.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*The target of Diplomatic Immunity can still disable and deal damage to Poppy. Meanwhile, Poppy is usually very aggressive while the spell is active. Try to punish her for selecting you as the target.*Fighting against Poppy in the jungle can be dangerous due to Heroic Charge. Try to catch her out in the open.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Valiant Fighter</name>
      <iconPath>Poppy_ValiantFighter.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>All physical and magic damage dealt to Poppy that exceeds 10% of her current health is reduced by 50%. This does not reduce damage from structures.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Devastating Blow</name>
      <cost>55/55/55/55/55 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>8/7/6/5/4</cooldown>
      <iconPath>PoppyDevastatingBlow.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Poppy crushes her opponent, dealing attack damage (+0.6) plus 20/40/60/80/100 and 8% of her target's maximum health as magic damage. The bonus damage dealt cannot exceed 75/150/225/300/375.</effect>
      <description>Poppy crushes her opponent, dealing attack damage plus a flat amount and 8% of her target's max health as bonus damage. The bonus damage cannot exceed a threshold based on rank.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Paragon of Demacia</name>
      <cost>70/75/80/85/90 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>12/12/12/12/12</cooldown>
      <iconPath>PoppyDefenseOfDemacia.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: Upon receiving damage from or dealing damage with a basic attack, Poppy's armor and damage are increased by 1.5/2/2.5/3/3.5 for 5 seconds. This effect can stack 10 times. Active: Poppy gains max stacks of Paragon of Demacia and her movement speed is increased by 17/19/21/23/25% for 5 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Passive: Upon receiving damage from or dealing damage with a basic attack, Poppy's armor and damage are increased for 5 seconds. This effect can stack 10 times. Active: Poppy gains max stacks of Paragon of Demacia and her movement speed is increased for 5 seconds.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Heroic Charge</name>
      <cost>60/65/70/75/80 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>12/11/10/9/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Poppy_HeroicCharge.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Poppy charges at an enemy and carries them for a short distance. The initial impact deals 50/75/100/125/150 (+0.4) magic damage. If they collide with terrain, her target takes 75/125/175/225/275 (+0.4) magic damage and will be stunned for 1.5/1.5/1.5/1.5/1.5 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Poppy charges at an enemy and carries them further. The initial impact deals a small amount of damage, and if they collide with terrain, her target will take a high amount of damage and be stunned.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Diplomatic Immunity</name>
      <cost>100/100/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>140/120/100</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Poppy_DiplomaticImmunity.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>For 6/7/8 seconds, Poppy is immune to any damage and abilities from enemies other than her target enemy champion. In addition, Poppy's attacks deal 20/30/40% increased damage to the marked target.</effect>
      <description>Poppy focuses intently on a single enemy champion, dealing increased damage to them. Poppy is immune to any damage and abilities from enemies other than her target.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1054</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3057</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1027</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3180</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3132</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3143</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3005</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>