<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>41</id>
  <name>Gangplank</name>
  <displayName>Gangplank</displayName>
  <title>the Saltwater Scourge</title>
  <iconPath>Gangplank_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Gangplank_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>carry,melee</tags>
  <description>Gangplank was born the son of the dread pirate captain Vincent the Shadow - one of the most wealthy and feared pirates in all of Blue Flame Island. One might think this would have spoiled the boy with a cushioned life of privilege, but the truth is quite the opposite. Growing up in the city of Bilgewater isn't easy; pirates are not known for their compassion, and that most certainly extends to their families. Vincent wanted his son to grow up tough and strong, so he was extremely hard on the young Gangplank. Even as a child, Gangplank was as mean as a snake and is said to have slept with his eyes open. As he grew, the young man rapidly became the most ruthless and feared pirate in all of Bilgewater, and his daddy was never more proud than on the day of his son's eighteenth birthday - when Gangplank stabbed his old man in the back and claimed the famed pirate ship, the Dead Pool, for his own. The continent of Valoran, however, is a dangerous place for pirates; Gangplank could read the writing on the wall. The den of pirates known as Bilgewater would soon be pulled down by the undertow of Valoranian politics and the Institute of War. It was time for Bilgewater to have their own champion to represent them in the League of Legends, and who better than the fiercest pirate of them all? It is said that Gangplank has enough power and favor to claim the title of the Pirate King back home, but that he is simply biding his time and building his reputation as a champion before he returns to a life of piracy. Yo ho, blow the man down. Or at least shoot him when his back is turned and steal all his booty.</description>
  <quote />
  <quoteAuthor />
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>345</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>16.5</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.3</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>215</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>40</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.3</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.14</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.85</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.15</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>495</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>81</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>54</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>6</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>4</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>5</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>7</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Parrrley applies On Hit effects like Frozen Mallet or Black Cleaver.*Paying attention to low-health enemies on the map can land you a surprise kill with Cannon Barrage.*Try placing Cannon Barrage on the path of escape to cut off fleeing enemies.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Parrrley deals a high amount of physical damage. Items that grant armor can help if an enemy Gangplank is doing well.*Grog-Soaked Blade reduces healing, including health potions. It can be beneficial to wait until the debuff fades before using them.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130216172601</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Grog-Soaked Blade</name>
      <iconPath>Pirate_GrogSoakedBlade.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Gangplank's basic attacks and Parrrley apply a poison that deals magic damage each second and slows movement speed. Lasts 3 seconds and stacks up to 3 times.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Parrrley</name>
      <cost>50/55/60/65/70 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>5/5/5/5/5</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Pirate_Parley.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Gangplank shoots a target unit for 20/45/70/95/120 (+) physical damage. If Parrrley deals a killing blow, Gangplank gains 4/5/6/7/8 extra gold and half the mana cost is refunded. Parrrley can crit and applies on hit effects as if a melee basic attack. Total Gold Plundered: gold.</effect>
      <description>Gangplank takes aim and shoots an enemy unit with his pistol. If Parrrley deals a killing blow, he gains extra gold and half the mana cost is refunded.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Remove Scurvy</name>
      <cost>65/65/65/65/65 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>22/21/20/19/18</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Pirate_RemoveScurvy.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Consumes a large quantity of citrus fruit which clears any crowd control effects on him and heals him for 80/150/220/290/360 (+1) health.</effect>
      <description>Consumes a large quantity of citrus fruit which clears any crowd control effects on him and heals him.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Raise Morale</name>
      <cost>50/55/60/65/70 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>20/20/20/20/20</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Pirate_RaiseMorale.png</iconPath>
      <range>1300</range>
      <effect>Passive: Gangplank gains 8/10/12/14/16 Attack Damage and 3/4/5/6/7% Movement Speed. Active: Gangplank fires his pistol into the air, disabling his passive boost but increasing his Attack Damage by 12/19/26/33/40 and Movement Speed by 8/11/14/17/20% and nearby allied champions' Attack Damage and Movement Speed by half that amount for 7 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Gangplank fires a shot into the air, increasing nearby allied champions' attack damage and movement speed.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Cannon Barrage</name>
      <cost>100/100/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>120/115/110</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Pirate_CannonBarrage.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Signals Gangplank's ship to fire upon an area for 7/7/7 seconds, slowing enemies in the area by 25/25/25% for the duration. Cannonballs rain upon the area, each causing 75/120/165 (+0.2) magic damage.</effect>
      <description>Gangplank signals his ship to fire upon an area for 6 seconds, slowing enemies and dealing damage in random locations within the area.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1054</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3004</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3072</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3044</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3180</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3022</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3005</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>