<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>58</id>
  <name>Renekton</name>
  <displayName>Renekton</displayName>
  <title>the Butcher of the Sands</title>
  <iconPath>Renekton_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Renekton_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,melee</tags>
  <description>On a faraway world, Renekton was born a member of a race of bestial guardians created to serve as the rulers and protectors of their people. Alongside his brother Nasus, Renekton oversaw the upkeep of the Great Library, which served as both a vault of ancient knowledge and the repository of the teachings of the Cycle of Life and Death. While the enlightened Nasus taught those scholars who came to study, Renekton served as the Great Library's gatekeeper. He could sense the true natures of those who sought Nasus' teachings, and he sent away those with dark ambitions. Over time, however, his repeated exposure to this evil infected his mind. He grew furious with the malevolence in the hearts of men, and as he descended deeper into madness, he discovered he could quell the fury by cutting the evil from the men who possessed it. Unfortunately, the relief was as short-lived as the subjects, and the ''butcher's rage'', as it came to be known, would resurge even stronger. Consumed by his anger, Renekton turned on the one being who could defeat him -- his own brother. Nasus pleaded with Renekton to see reason. Realizing that he was beyond redemption, the despondent Nasus valiantly struck down his wayward sibling. Defenseless, Renekton waited eagerly for death's release. It never came. He was spared when summoners from the League of Legends claimed his brother. Caught in the wake of this powerful spell, Renekton tumbled for what seemed like ages between realities. When he finally emerged, he fell deep into the sewers of Zaun. Insane with fury, Renekton languished in his newfound home, driven senseless by his rage. That is until, by happenstance, he caught a familiar scent in the air. Believing that the familiar scent would guide him to the solace that was fading from his memory, he traced his brother to the Institute of War.</description>
  <quote>My brother has become hollow. Full of rage, but empty.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Nasus, the Curator of the Sands.</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>345</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>15.2</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.8</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>100</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>0</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>0</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.34</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.15</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>426</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>87</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>53.12</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.1</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>5</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>2</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>3</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>9</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Slice and Dice excels at harassing maneuvers. Slice in, follow up with another skill and then Dice back out to safety.*Cull the Meek drains an enormous amount of life when used in the middle of the fray. You can use this to bait opponents into thinking you are weaker than you really are.*Cooldown reduction is especially good for Renekton, allowing him to both quickly build up and use his Fury.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Pay close attention to Renekton's Fury gauge as that will usually signify when he is about to attack.*Keeping Renekton from being able to fight and gain Fury by continually harassing him will severely reduce the effectiveness of his abilities.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Reign of Anger</name>
      <iconPath>Renekton_Predator.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Renekton gains Fury for every autoattack he makes. This Fury can empower his abilities with bonus effects. Additionally, Renekton gains bonus Fury when he is low on life.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Cull the Meek</name>
      <cooldown>8/8/8/8/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Renekton_Cleave.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Renekton swings his blade, dealing 60/90/120/150/180 (+) physical damage to nearby enemies and gains 5% of the damage dealt as Health (20% for champions), up to 50/75/100/125/150. Enemy champions heal for 4x as much. 50 Fury Bonus: Damage increased to 90/135/180/225/270 (+). Heal percent increased to 10%, up to 150/225/300/375/450. </effect>
      <description>Renekton swings his blade, dealing moderate physical damage to all targets around him and heals for a small portion of the damage dealt. If he has more than 50 Fury, his damage and heal are increased.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Ruthless Predator</name>
      <cooldown>13/12/11/10/9</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Renekton_Execute.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Renekton's next attack strikes twice, dealing physical damage (10/30/50/70/90 + 150/150/150/150/150% of his Attack Damage) and stuns for 0.75 seconds. Each hit applies on-hit effects. 50 Fury Bonus: Instead, Renekton attacks three times, dealing physical damage (15/45/75/105/135 + 225/225/225/225/225% of his Attack Damage) and stuns his target for 1.5 seconds. </effect>
      <description>Renekton slashes his target twice, dealing moderate physical damage and stuns them for 0.75 seconds. If Renekton has more than 50 Fury, he slashes his target three times, dealing high physical damage and stuns them for 1.5 seconds.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Slice and Dice</name>
      <cooldown>18/17/16/15/14</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Renekton_SliceAndDice.png</iconPath>
      <range>450</range>
      <effect>Slice: Renekton dashes, dealing 30/60/90/120/150 (+) physical damage. Hitting an enemy grants the ability to use Dice for 4 seconds. Dice: Renekton dashes, dealing 30/60/90/120/150 (+) physical damage. Dice - 50 Fury Bonus: Damage increased to 45/90/135/180/225 (+). Enemies hit have 15/20/25/30/35% reduced Armor for 4 seconds. </effect>
      <description>Renekton dashes, dealing damage to units along the way. Empowered, Renekton deals bonus damage and reduces the armor of units hit.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Dominus</name>
      <cooldown>120/120/120</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Renekton_Dominus.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Renekton surrounds himself with dark energies for 15 seconds, gaining 300/450/600 Health. While active, he deals 40/70/100 (+0.1) magic damage to nearby enemies and gains 5 Fury per second.</effect>
      <description>Renekton transforms into the Tyrant form, gaining bonus Health and dealing damage to enemies around him. While in this form, Renekton gains Fury periodically.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3044</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3065</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3143</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3132</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3022</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3156</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>