<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>107</id>
  <name>Rengar</name>
  <displayName>Rengar</displayName>
  <title>the Pridestalker</title>
  <iconPath>Rengar_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Rengar_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,jungler,melee,stealth</tags>
  <description>On every wall of his den, the trophy hunter Rengar mounts the heads, horns, claws, and fangs of the most lethal creatures in Valoran. Though his collection is extensive, he remains unsatisfied, tirelessly seeking greater game. He takes time with every kill, studying his prey, learning, and preparing himself for the next encounter with the one monster he never managed to defeat. Rengar never knew his real parents, but was raised by a human who was revered as a legendary hunter. He was an ideal pupil, intently absorbing the lessons of his father, and improving them with his uncanny feral instincts. Before his mane had fully grown, Rengar set off on his own and claimed a wide territory for himself. Along its perimeter, he mounted the skulls of his slain prey - a warning to would-be aggressors. He thought undisputed reign of a region would fulfill him, but instead, he grew restless. No beasts in his domain proved challenging prey, and without formidable adversaries to push his limits, Rengar's spirit waned. He feared that no worthwhile game remained, that he would never again feel the thrill of the hunt. Just when things seemed their bleakest, he encountered the monster. It was a disturbing, alien thing, distinctly out of place in his world. It bore huge scything claws and devoured any animal that strayed across its path. Overzealous at the prospect of a challenge, Rengar ambushed the monster in haste. It far outclassed anything he'd hunted before. Their fight was savage, and each suffered crippling wounds. Rengar lost an eye, but the most grievous blow was to his pride. He had never before failed to make the kill. Worse yet, the severity of his injuries forced him to retreat. Over the following days, he hovered on the threshold between life and death. He was wracked with pain, but beneath it, he felt a glimmer of joy. The hunt was on. If such powerful beings existed in the world, he would find them, and stack their heads high. The monster, however, was a kill he wanted to savor. On his den's largest wall, he reserves a space for the beast's head, a trophy he swears will one day be the centerpiece of his collection.</description>
  <quote>Prey on the weak and you will survive, prey on the strong and you will live.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Rengar</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>345</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>16</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>5</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>0</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>0</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.72</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.08</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>435</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>85</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>55</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>4</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>2</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>5</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>7</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Use Rengar's ultimate to find and assassinate high priority targets in team fights and skirmishes.*A lot of Rengar's power comes from empowered abilities he uses at the right moment - choose wisely!*Make sure to take paths through brush when chasing opponents to take advantage of Rengar's passive.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Rengar gains an empowered ability when his resource bar is full. Try to confront him when it's low.*Rengar's passive enables him to leap out of brush, so avoid fighting him when near bushes.*Rengar's ultimate grants him temporary stealth, so try to avoid traveling alone when injured.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Unseen Predator</name>
      <iconPath>Rengar_Passive.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>While in brush or stealth Rengar will leap at the target when using his basic attack. Rengar builds 1 point of Ferocity with each ability he uses on enemies. When reaching 5 points of Ferocity, Rengar's next ability becomes empowered, granting it a bonus effect. </description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Savagery</name>
      <cooldown>8/7.5/7/6.5/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>RengarQ.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>The next basic attack within 6 seconds deals 30/60/90/120/150 (+) physical damage. Grants % Attack Speed for 4/4/4/4/4 seconds. Ferocity bonus: Additionally deals 100/100/100/100/100% of Rengar's Attack Damage (+) in bonus damage, and the Attack Speed bonus is doubled.</effect>
      <description>Rengar's next basic attack deals bonus damage and grants him increased Attack Speed. Ferocity Bonus: Rengar deals enhanced damage and doubles his Attack Speed bonus.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Battle Roar</name>
      <cooldown>0/0/0/0/0</cooldown>
      <iconPath>RengarW.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Deals 50/80/110/140/170 (+0.8) magic damage to enemies in the area. Grants 15/22/29/36/43 Armor and Magic resist for 3 seconds if an enemy is hit. Ferocity bonus: Rengar restores Health.</effect>
      <description>Rengar lets out a battle roar, damaging enemies and gaining bonus Armor and Magic Resist for a short duration. Ferocity Bonus: Rengar heals for a large amount.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Bola Strike</name>
      <cooldown>12/11/10/9/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>RengarE.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Throws a bola dealing 60/105/150/195/240 (+) physical damage and slowing an enemy by 50/55/60/65/70%, Enemy Movement Speed recovers over 2.5 seconds. Ferocity bonus: Roots the target for 1/1/1/1/1 second.</effect>
      <description>Rengar throws a bola at his target, slowing them for a short duration. Ferocity Bonus: Roots the target for 1 second.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Thrill of the Hunt</name>
      <cooldown>140/105/70</cooldown>
      <iconPath>RengarUlt.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Activates predatory instincts stealthing Rengar after 1 second (delayed up to 3 seconds if taking damage), and revealing enemy Champions within 2000/3000/4000 range. Rengar gains 20/25/30% Movement Speed and 5 Ferocity over 3.75 seconds. Lasts seconds or until Rengar uses an ability that removes his stealth.</effect>
      <description>Rengar activates his predatory instincts, stealthing and revealing all enemy Champions in a large radius around him. He gains Movement Speed and rapidly generates Ferocity while stealthed. </description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3166</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1062</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3166</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3166</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3065</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3083</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>