<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>15</id>
  <name>Sivir</name>
  <displayName>Sivir</displayName>
  <title>the Battle Mistress</title>
  <iconPath>Sivir_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Sivir_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>carry,pusher,ranged,recommended</tags>
  <description>The beautiful and deadly champion known as Sivir has been a favorite of League summoners for close to a decade. A soldier-for-hire outside of the Fields of Justice, she is the embodiment of a highly successful mercenary on modern day Runeterra. Sivir has little interest in the ''cribbage sheets'' - as she calls them - of League influence bartering. Instead, she is motivated by material wealth and riches, and she is paid handsomely for her services. Sivir is one of the wealthiest individuals found anywhere on Valoran. Sivir owns multiple residences in a number of different city-states, as well as ownership stakes in a number of businesses all across Valoran. Her detractors, either envious of her success or acrimonious of her flexible morality, have begun to use Sivir as a symbol of what is wrong with the mercenary nature of the League. Sivir dismisses her critics, saying that while her personal code of ethics is less ruthless than her competitors, ''Everyone has a price.'' Sivir has earned many titles and accolades throughout her illustrious career, but the one she held until recently was ''Battle Mistress of Noxus''. Now she is simply known as ''The Battle Mistress'' after breaking her contract with the Noxian High Command. Sivir dared to object to the Noxian war against the peaceful island state of Ionia, though less about the morality of the issue than the planning behind it; her predictions of a bloody stalemate came true when the Ionians held off the relentless assaults of the Noxians. Claiming that the Noxian High Command had lost its direction, she left Noxus and made her services available to the Institute of War. The Noxian High Command has sent a number of contracted assassins to deal with its rogue mercenary, but none have delivered her or survived.</description>
  <quote>Time and time again, Sivir proves that she has earned the right to call herself 'The Battle Mistress'.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Jax</quoteAuthor>
  <range>500</range>
  <moveSpeed>335</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>12.75</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.25</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>203</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>43</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.3</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.1</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.85</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.11</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>378</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>82</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>49</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>2.9</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>3</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>1</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>3</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>9</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Sivir's Boomerang Blade returns to her after reaching the max range, so you can shift position to hit enemies who would otherwise have evaded it.*Using Frozen Mallet or Phage in conjunction with On the Hunt ensures that you and your teammates are able to hit opponents non-stop.*Ricochet resets Sivir's basic attack timer on activation, so activating this immediately after landing a normal basic attack will maximize damage output.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Boomerang Blade costs a lot of mana to cast, so dodging it sets Sivir back. If it hits you on the way out, avoid its path on the way back.*Sivir is a powerful pushing champion, so leaving her unattended in a lane for too long will often result in your turrets being destroyed.*When laning against Sivir as a caster, it may be possible to throw off Sivir's timing on her Spell Shield by faking an advance and backing off.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Fleet of Foot</name>
      <iconPath>Sivir_Sprint.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Sivir gains a short burst of Movement Speed when she attacks an enemy champion.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Boomerang Blade</name>
      <cost>70/80/90/100/110 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>9/9/9/9/9</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sivir_SpiralBlade.png</iconPath>
      <range>1075</range>
      <effect>Sivir hurls her crossblade like a boomerang, which deals 60/105/150/195/240 (+) (+0.5) physical damage to the first unit and 20/20/20/20/20% reduced damage to each subsequent target down to a minimum of 40/40/40/40/40%.</effect>
      <description>Sivir hurls her crossblade like a boomerang, dealing damage each way.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Ricochet</name>
      <cost>40/40/40/40/40 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>7/6/5/4/3</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sivir_Ricochet.png</iconPath>
      <range>20</range>
      <effect>Sivir's next basic attack will bounce to 5/5/5/5/5 additional targets, dealing 20/35/50/65/80 (+) to the first target and 20/20/20/20/20% less damage with each bounce (only the first hit procs item effects).</effect>
      <description>Sivir's next basic attack will bounce between targets, dealing reduced damage with each successive hit.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Spell Shield</name>
      <cost>75/75/75/75/75 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>22/19/16/13/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sivir_SpellBlock.png</iconPath>
      <range>20</range>
      <effect>Sivir creates a magical barrier for 3/3/3/3/3 seconds that blocks the next incoming enemy ability. If an ability is blocked by the shield, Sivir regains 150/150/150/150/150 Mana.</effect>
      <description>Creates a magical barrier that blocks a single enemy ability cast on Sivir. She receives Mana back if a spell is blocked.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>On The Hunt</name>
      <cost>100/100/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>100/90/80</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sivir_Deadeye.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Sivir's battle prowess emanates for 10/10/10 seconds, increasing her Movement Speed by 20/20/20% and Attack Speed by 30/45/60%. Nearby allies gain the Movement Speed bonus and half of the Attack Speed bonus for the duration.</effect>
      <description>Sivir leads her allies into battle granting them increased Movement and Attack Speeds for a period of time.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3004</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3072</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1062</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3178</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3004</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3046</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>