<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>68</id>
  <name>Rumble</name>
  <displayName>Rumble</displayName>
  <title>the Mechanized Menace</title>
  <iconPath>Rumble_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Rumble_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>mage,melee,pusher</tags>
  <description>Even amongst yordles, Rumble was always the runt of the litter. As such, he was used to being bullied. In order to survive, he had to be scrappier and more resourceful than his peers. He developed a quick temper and a reputation for getting even, no matter who crossed him. This made him something of a loner, but he didn't mind. He liked to tinker, preferring the company of gadgets, and he could usually be found rummaging through the junkyard. He showed great potential as a mechanic. His teachers recommended him for enrollment at the Yordle Academy of Science and Progress in Piltover, where he may very well have become one of Heimerdinger's esteemed proteges, but Rumble refused to go. He believed that Heimerdinger and his associates were ''sellouts,'' trading superior yordle technology to humans for nothing more than a pat on the head while yordles remained the butt of their jokes. When a group of human graduates from the Yordle Academy sailed to Bandle City to visit the place where their mentor was born and raised, Rumble couldn't resist the temptation to see them face-to-face (so to speak). He only intended to get a good look at the humans, but four hours and several choice words later, he returned home bruised and bloodied with an earful about how he was an embarrassment to ''enlightened'' yordles like Heimerdinger. The next morning he left Bandle City without a word, and wasn't seen again for months. When he returned, he was at the helm of a clanking, mechanized monstrosity. He marched it to the center of town amidst dumbfounded onlookers and there announced that he would join the League of Legends to show the world what yordle-tech was really capable of, without hiding behind a foreign banner.</description>
  <quote>Ugh, it's gonna take forever to scrape your face off my suit!</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Rumble</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>345</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>16</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>100</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>0</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>0</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.4</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.12</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>450</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>80</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>55.66</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.2</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>6</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>8</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>8</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>3</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Try and pace yourself to stay in the Danger Zone to maximize your effectiveness. It is easy to overheat if you rapidly use your abilities.*Try and keep targets in the range of your Flamespitter. It can deal a lot of damage overtime.*If you are winning a fight you can use your ultimate to wall off an escape path.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Watch Rumble's heat bar carefully. If you see him Overheat, go in for the kill while his skills are disabled.*Rumble's ultimate can deal a lot of damage if you stay inside the area of effect. When you see the missiles falling, move out of the way as quickly as possible.*Rumble deals almost entirely magic damage. Build some Magic Resistance to reduce his damage.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Junkyard Titan</name>
      <iconPath>Rumble_Junkyard Titan1.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Every spell Rumble casts gives him Heat. When he reaches 50% Heat he reaches Danger Zone, granting all his basic abilities bonus effects. When he reaches 100% heat, he starts Overheating, granting his basic attacks bonus damage, but making him unable to cast spells for a few seconds. </description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Flamespitter</name>
      <cooldown>6/6/6/6/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Rumble_Flamespitter.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Rumble torches his opponents, dealing 90/160/230/300/370 (+1.35) magic damage in a cone over 3 seconds. This spell deals half damage to minions. Danger Zone Bonus: Deals 25% bonus damage.</effect>
      <description>Rumble torches opponents in front of him, dealing magic damage in a cone for 3 seconds. While in Danger Zone this damage is increased. </description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Scrap Shield</name>
      <cooldown>6/6/6/6/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Rumble_Scrap Shield.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Rumble tosses up a shield for 2 seconds that absorbs 50/80/110/140/170 (+0.4) damage. Rumble also gains an additional 10/15/20/25/30% Movement Speed for 1 second. Danger Zone Bonus: 25% increase in shield health and Movement Speed.</effect>
      <description>Rumble pulls up a shield, protecting him from damage and granting him a quick burst of speed. While in Danger Zone, the shield strength and speed bonus is increased. </description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Electro Harpoon</name>
      <cooldown>0.5/0.5/0.5/0.5/0.5</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Rumble_Electro Harpoon.png</iconPath>
      <range>850</range>
      <effect>Rumble shoots his opponent with up to 2 tasers, dealing 55/85/115/145/175 (+0.5) magic damage and applying a stacking slow of 15/20/25/30/35% for 3 seconds. Danger Zone Bonus: Damage and slow percentage increased by 25%. After using this ability you may cast it a second time at no cost within 3 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Rumble launches a taser, electrocuting his target with magic damage and slowing their Movement Speed. A second shot can be fired within 3 seconds. While in Danger Zone the damage and slow percentage is increased. </description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>The Equalizer</name>
      <cooldown>105/90/75</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Rumble_R.png</iconPath>
      <range>1750</range>
      <effect>Rumble launches a line of rockets that creates a burning trail for 5 seconds. Enemies in the area have their Movement Speed slowed by 35/35/35% and take 130/185/240 (+) magic damage each second. You can control the placement of this attack by clicking and dragging your mouse in a line.</effect>
      <description>Rumble fires off a group of rockets, creating a wall of flames that damages and slows enemies. </description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1054</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3145</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3001</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3145</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3001</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1054</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3152</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3001</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>