<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>80</id>
  <name>Pantheon</name>
  <displayName>Pantheon</displayName>
  <title>the Artisan of War</title>
  <iconPath>Pantheon_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Pantheon_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>assassin,melee</tags>
  <description>Far above the clouds on Mount Targon resides a stalwart tribe of people known as the Rakkor who still revere combat and war as ultimate artforms. They remember the Rune Wars of Runeterra and know that the League of Legends can only repress the rising tides of violence for so long. Each member of the tribe is bred to be a disciplined and vicious warrior, preferring to battle soldiers of either the Noxian or Demacian armies only when outnumbered at least ten to one. Rakkor warriors are trained not only to be as lethal with their bare hands as the most capable martial artists, but also to fiercely wield the many relic-weapons of the tribe. Such treasures have been handed down from generation to generation, and have harnessed the mystical nature of Runeterra in their very cores. These relic-weapons are among the most dangerous in existence - and it comes as no surprise that they have found their way to the League of Legends in the hands of Pantheon. This stone-faced warrior is a paragon of his people, his very existence an anthem of exultation to the art of combat. Pantheon found it insulting that the people of Valoran would install an organization to replace war, complete with so-called champions, without including the Rakkor. Gathering the blessings of his tribe and armed with the relics of his ancestors, he has descended on the League to show the world a true warrior. He cares not who he fights, and cares nothing for the pageantry or prestige of a League champion, but lives only for the austere glory of battle. As long as Pantheon breathes, he thirsts for another foe to vanquish.</description>
  <quote>I was hoping they had more reinforcements.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Pantheon, standing amidst the pieces of a brutalized Noxian battalion.</quoteAuthor>
  <range>150</range>
  <moveSpeed>355</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>17.1</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.9</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>210</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>34</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.32</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.09</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.35</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.13</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>433</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>87</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>50.7</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>2.9</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>3</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>3</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>3</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>9</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Using Aegis of Zeonia quickly followed by Heartseeker Strike can devastate your enemies.*Using Spear Shot frequently in a battle, along with attack speed items, can help defensively by charging Aegis Protection.*Using Grand Skyfall to assist your allies across the map can quickly turn the tides of battle, putting your allies at an advantage.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Keeping yourself hidden in brush can make it harder for Pantheon to target you with Grand Skyfall.*Watch out for when Pantheon has a stunning or snaring partner in lane with him (example: Morgana, Sion) as he can cause devastating damage with his Heartseeker Strike.*Use your auto-attack to break his shield before casting your abilities.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Aegis Protection</name>
      <iconPath>Pantheon_AOZ.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>After attacking or casting spells 4 times, Pantheon will block the next incoming basic attack or turret attack.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Spear Shot</name>
      <cost>45/45/45/45/45 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>4/4/4/4/4</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Pantheon_SpearShot.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Pantheon hurls his spear at an opponent, dealing 65/105/145/185/225 (+) physical damage. </effect>
      <description>Pantheon hurls his spear at an opponent, dealing damage.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Aegis of Zeonia</name>
      <cost>55/55/55/55/55 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>13/12/11/10/9</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Pantheon_LeapBash.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Pantheon leaps at the target enemy champion and deals 50/75/100/125/150 (+1) magic damage and stuns them for 1/1/1/1/1 second. Pantheon also instantly refreshes his Aegis Protection.</effect>
      <description>Pantheon leaps at an enemy and bashes the enemy with his shield, stunning them. After finishing the attack, Pantheon readies himself to block the next attack.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Heartseeker Strike</name>
      <cost>45/50/55/60/65 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/9/8/7/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Pantheon_HSS.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: Pantheon's basic attacks and Spear Shot gain 100% critical strike chance against targets below 15/15/15/15/15% health. Active: Pantheon focuses and deals 3/3/3/3/3 swift strikes in front of him for 13/23/33/43/53 (+) physical damage per strike. Deals double damage to champions.</effect>
      <description>Pantheon focuses and unleashes 3 swift strikes to the area in front of him, dealing double damage to champions. Pantheon also becomes more aware of his enemy's vital spots, allowing him to always crit enemies below 15% health.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Grand Skyfall</name>
      <cost>125/125/125 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>150/135/120</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Pantheon_GrandSkyfall.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Pantheon gathers his strength and then leaps high into the air, crashing down at the target area a few seconds later. Deals up to 400/700/1000 (+1) magic damage to units at the center (down to 50/50/50% at the edge) and slows their Movement Speed by 35/35/35% for 1 second.</effect>
      <description>Pantheon composes himself then leaps into the air to a target, striking all enemy units in an area. Enemies closer to the impact point take more damage.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1005</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3028</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3044</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3155</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3044</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3156</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>