<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>14</id>
  <name>Sion</name>
  <displayName>Sion</displayName>
  <title>the Undead Champion</title>
  <iconPath>Sion_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Sion_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,melee</tags>
  <description>Prior to the creation of the League of Legends, the city-states of Demacia and Noxus were locked in a brutal series of on-again-off-again wars that spanned the course of centuries. Both powers sought an advantage over the other, but Noxus was the city-state willing to forego conventional morality to achieve its goals. Only brute strength and the will to use it mattered to Noxus, and this is best exemplified in the murderous warrior, Sion. Used by the Noxians as a human battering ram, Sion would be sent thundering ahead of Noxian troops. He would mercilessly slaughter foes with his large double-bladed axe, ''Chopper''. His complete disregard for caution ultimately cost him his life, as he was captured and summarily executed by Demacian forces. The Demacians thought that the beheading of Sion would be the end of his bloodthirsty ways. Death, however, was merely the beginning of Sion's rise to power. The famed Noxian assassin, Katarina, recovered Sion's remains and Noxian necromancers reanimated the behemoth to serve Noxus once again. Sion's reanimation actually bestowed new powers on him and increased the potency of his existing abilities, making him even more of a terror to behold on the battlefield. The Noxian High Command had a powerful new weapon in their hands - one they have brought to bear as a champion in the League of Legends. Even though Sion's increased powers would make him a powerful tool for the High Command's use outside the Fields of Justice, Noxus no longer risks losing one of their greatest champions in the League to chance or circumstance; Sion's days as a front-line fighter for Noxus' military conquests are at an end.</description>
  <quote>For Noxus, death is a promotion.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Pantheon</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>345</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>17.75</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.25</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>200</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>40</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.26</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.08</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.58</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.19</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>403</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>104</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>55.52</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.1875</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>8</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>7</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>4</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>5</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Using Enrage early helps Sion in the late game. When Sion kills something his health is increased permanently and Enrage makes it easier to last hit resulting in better gold farming.*Cryptic Gaze and Cannibalize can both be used in a defensive manner to save allies and sustain pushes.*Death's Caress and Cryptic Gaze scale very well with AP and can greatly increase your ganking strength.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*If Death's Caress is on Sion, it is often worth casting a damaging spell to ensure that the shield doesn't explode.*Try disabling Sion while his ultimate is active.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Feel No Pain</name>
      <iconPath>Sion_FeelNoPain.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Sion has a 40% chance to ignore up to 30/40/50 damage each time he is attacked.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Cryptic Gaze</name>
      <cost>100/100/100/100/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>12/11/10/9/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sion_CrypticGaze.png</iconPath>
      <range>550</range>
      <effect>Blasts a single enemy, dealing 70/125/180/240/300 (+0.9) magic damage and stunning for 1.5 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Sion's stare terrifies a single enemy, dealing damage and stunning them.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Death's Caress</name>
      <cost>70/80/90/100/110 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>8/8/8/8/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sion_DeathsCaress.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Sion surrounds himself with a shield which absorbs 100/150/200/250/300 (+0.9) damage. If the shield is not destroyed in 10 seconds, it will explode, dealing 100/150/200/250/300 (+0.9) magic damage to surrounding enemies. Cast again after 4 seconds to manually detonate.</effect>
      <description>Sion surrounds himself with a damage-absorbing shield. If the shield is not destroyed in 10 seconds then it will explode, dealing damage to surrounding enemies. Cast again after 4 seconds to manually detonate.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Enrage</name>
      <cost>6/8/10/12/14 Health per Attack</cost>
      <cooldown>0/0/0/0/0</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sion_SpiritRage.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Toggle: Sion's Attack Damage is increased by 25/35/45/55/65 and he permanently gains 1/1.5/2/2.5/3 maximum Health per kill. This bonus is doubled against Champions, large minions and large monsters Total Health gained: +</effect>
      <description>While active Sion gains Attack Damage at the cost of Health on each basic attack. Additonally, he permanently increases his maximum Health whenever he kills a unit.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Cannibalism</name>
      <cost>100/100/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>90/90/90</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sion_Cannibalism.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Grants Sion 50/75/100% Life Steal and 50/50/50% Attack Speed for 20 seconds. Additionally, Sion's basic attacks heal surrounding allies for 25/37.5/50% of the damage dealt.</effect>
      <description>Sion consumes some of his enemies' life force on each attack, leeching health to himself and nearby allies. The smell of flesh also renews Sion's fervor, increasing his Attack Speed. </description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3057</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3102</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1063</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3057</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3180</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3102</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>