<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>4</id>
  <name>TwistedFate</name>
  <displayName>Twisted Fate</displayName>
  <title>the Card Master</title>
  <iconPath>TwistedFate_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>TwistedFate_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>assassin,pusher,ranged</tags>
  <description>Although born to poor gypsy parents, the champion known as Twisted Fate was able to gamble his way to prosperity as a card shark in the seedy underground gambling circuits of Demacia and Noxus. No matter how close the authorities came to catching him, the rogue always found a way to slip through their fingers. Despite his good fortune, he was never able to win that which he truly desired - the ability to control magic. When Twisted Fate learned of an experiment being conducted in Zaun that might help him with his wish, he did the only thing a gambler of his worth could do - he went all in and volunteered for the experiment. Conducted by the infamous Dr. Xavier Rath, Twisted Fate was told that the wager for such participation might be steep. He might change forever, or nothing might happen, or he might die horribly. Pain, however, was likely a part of the deal no matter the outcome. These were hardly the worst odds the gambler had faced; his hopes raised, Twisted Fate underwent the experiment, enduring what he must for a chance at his dream. Then, it ended - with seemingly no effect whatsoever. The gypsy rogue flew into a murderous rage, but, before he could strike down the team, he suddenly teleported himself miles away. With a sly grin, he realized his luck had won out yet again. He now brings his luck and rakish charm to the Institute of War, where he is the Champion of choice for many - especially the gambling kind. To this day, Twisted Fate has avoided his inevitable reunion with Dr. Rath. The Card Master knows, however, that a confrontation is coming. While the future may be mysterious and unknown to most, Twisted Fate is certain that his future lies within the cards.</description>
  <quote />
  <quoteAuthor />
  <range>525</range>
  <moveSpeed>330</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>11.25</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.15</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>202</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>38</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.3</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.1</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.9</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.12</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>384</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>82</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>46.41</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>2</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>6</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>9</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>6</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Coordinate with your allies for the best time to use Destiny to ambush enemies.*Stealth characters often escape a battle with very low hit points. Take advantage of Destiny's ability to reveal stealthed units to finish them off.*Twisted Fate is viable as an Attack Damage or Ability Power character, letting him fit on many different team compositions.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Focus on dodging Wild Cards early when your champion doesn't have the hit points to afford getting hit.*If you have low health, use Destiny as an indicator to run to safety. It will give you a head start in escaping any possible ganks.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Loaded Dice</name>
      <iconPath>Cardmaster_SealFate.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Twisted Fate and his allies receive an additional 2 gold per kill.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Wild Cards</name>
      <cost>60/70/80/90/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>6/6/6/6/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Cardmaster_PowerCard.png</iconPath>
      <range>1450</range>
      <effect>Throws three cards that deal 60/110/160/210/260 (+0.65) magic damage to each enemy unit they pass through.</effect>
      <description>Twisted Fate throws three cards, dealing damage to each enemy unit they pass through.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Pick A Card</name>
      <cost>40/55/70/85/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>6/6/6/6/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>CardMaster_FatesGambit.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Cast once to shuffle the deck and again to choose your card, enhancing your next attack. Blue Card deals 40/60/80/100/120 (+) (+0.4) magic damage, restoring () mana (65% of the base damage and total AD, does not include AP). Red Card deals 30/45/60/75/90 (+) (+0.4) magic damage to units around the target and slows their movement speeds by 30/35/40/45/50%. Gold Card deals 15/22.5/30/37.5/45 (+) (+0.4) magic damage and stuns for 1/1.25/1.5/1.75/2 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Twisted Fate chooses a magic card from his deck, and uses that for his next attack, causing bonus effects.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Stacked Deck</name>
      <cooldown>20/20/20/20/20</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Cardmaster_RapidToss.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: Every 4/4/4/4/4 attacks, Twisted Fate deals an additional 55/80/105/130/155 (+0.4) magic damage. In addition, his attack speed is increased by 3/6/9/12/15% and his cooldowns are decreased by 3/6/9/12/15%.</effect>
      <description>Every 4 attacks, Twisted Fate deals bonus damage. In addition, his attack speed is increased and his cooldowns are decreased.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Destiny</name>
      <cost>150/125/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>150/135/120</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Destiny_temp.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Reveals all enemy champions (including stealthed champions) on the map for 6/8/10 seconds. While Destiny is active, Twisted Fate can teleport up to 5500/5500/5500 units away.</effect>
      <description>Twisted Fate predicts the fortunes of his foes, revealing all enemy champions and enabling the use of Gate, which teleports Twisted Fate to any target location.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3102</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1063</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3102</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>