<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>121</id>
  <name>Khazix</name>
  <displayName>Kha'Zix</displayName>
  <title>the Voidreaver</title>
  <iconPath>Khazix_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Khazix_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>assassin,melee,jungler,stealth</tags>
  <description>A vicious Void predator, Kha'Zix infiltrated Valoran to devour the land's most promising creatures. With each kill he absorbs his prey's strength, evolving to grow more powerful. Kha'Zix hungers most to conquer and consume Rengar, the one beast he considers his equal. When Kha'Zix crossed over into this world, he was fragile and ravenous. The animals he first encountered were too small to fuel the rapid evolution he craved. Kha'Zix focused his hunger on the most dangerous creatures he could find, risking his life to satisfy his need. With each kill he feasted and changed, becoming a stronger, faster predator. Kha'Zix soon chased his prey with unrestrained aggression, believing he was unstoppable. One day, while savoring a fresh kill, the predator became the prey. From cover a creature pounced in a blur of fangs and steel, tackling him to the ground. It roared in his face slashing and clawing, and Kha'Zix felt his blood spill for the first time. Screeching in fury, he sliced at the brute's eye driving it back. They fought from sunset to sunrise. Finally, near death, they reluctantly separated. As his wounds closed, Kha'Zix burned with anticipation at the idea of devouring one who could match the Void's strength. He resumed his search for powerful prey with renewed vigor. Someday, Kha'Zix will feast on Rengar.</description>
  <quote>Kill. Consume. Adapt.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Kha'Zix</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>350</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>15</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>260</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>40</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.35</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.1</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.25</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.15</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>430</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>85</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>50</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.1</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>4</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>6</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>7</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>9</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Enemies are considered isolated if they have no allies within a short distance. The damage of Taste Their Fear is massively increased against these targets.*Unseen Threat activates when Kha'zix cannot be seen by the enemy team. Reactivate by using brush or Void Assault. Don't forget to apply Unseen Threat by autoattacking enemy champions.*Kha'Zix has a great deal of freedom to choose where and when to fight. Pick your battles carefully to succeed.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Taste Their Fear deals bonus damage to targets that are isolated. Gain an advantage by fighting near allied minions, champions, or turrets.*Leap and Void Assault have long cooldowns. Kha'Zix is very vulnerable when these are not available.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130329110558</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Unseen Threat</name>
      <iconPath>Khazix_P.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>When Kha'Zix is not visible to the enemy team, he gains Unseen Threat, causing his next basic attack against an enemy Champion to deal bonus magic damage and slow.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Taste Their Fear</name>
      <cost>25/25/25/25/25 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>3.5/3.5/3.5/3.5/3.5</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Khazix_Q.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: Marks enemies who are isolated from nearby allies. Active: Deals 70/100/130/160/190 (+) physical damage. If the target is isolated, the amount is increased to 100/145/190/235/280 (+). Evolved Enlarged Claws: Increases damage to isolated enemies by 12/12/12/12/12% of their missing health (max 200/200/200/200/200 vs. monsters). Increases the range of Taste Their Fear and Kha'Zix's basic attacks by 50/50/50/50/50.</effect>
      <description>Kha'Zix passively marks enemies that are isolated from nearby allies. Taste Their Fear deals physical damage to a single target. Damage increased on isolated targets. If he chooses to Evolve Enlarged Claws , damage to isolated targets increases dramatically. Kha'Zix also gains increased range on his basic attacks and Taste Their Fear.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Void Spike</name>
      <cost>60/70/80/90/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>8/8/8/8/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Khazix_W.png</iconPath>
      <range>1000</range>
      <effect>Fires exploding spikes, dealing 75/115/155/195/235 (+) physical damage to all nearby enemies. Heals Kha'Zix for 40/70/100/130/160 (+) if he is within the explosion radius. Evolved Spike Racks: Void Spike fires three spikes in a cone. Consumes Unseen Threat to slow and damage all enemies struck.</effect>
      <description>Kha'Zix fires exploding spikes that deal physical damage to all nearby enemies. Kha'Zix is healed if he is also within the explosion radius. If he chooses to Evolve Spike Racks , Void Spike fires three spikes in a cone. This effect consumes Unseen Threat to slow and damage all enemies struck.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Leap</name>
      <cost>50/50/50/50/50 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>22/20/18/16/14</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Khazix_E.png</iconPath>
      <range>600</range>
      <effect>Leaps to a target area, dealing 65/100/135/170/205 (+) physical damage. Evolved Wings: Increases Leap's range. On champion kill or assist, Leap's cooldown resets.</effect>
      <description>Kha'Zix leaps to an area, dealing physical damage upon landing. If he chooses to Evolve Wings , Leap's range increases dramatically. Also, on champion kill or assist, Leap's cooldown resets.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Void Assault</name>
      <cost>100/100/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>100/90/80</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Khazix_R.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: Ranking up Void Assault allows Kha'Zix to evolve one of his abilities. Active: Stealths for 1/1/1 second. Activates Unseen Threat and increases Kha'Zix's Movement Speed by 40/40/40%. Void Assault can be cast a second time within 10/10/10 seconds. Evolved Active Camouflage: Void Assault can be cast three times. Kha'Zix takes 40/40/40% reduced damage while in stealth.</effect>
      <description>Each rank allows Kha'Zix to evolve one of his abilities, giving it a unique additional effect. When activated, Void Assault stealths Kha'Zix, triggers Unseen Threat, and increases Movement Speed. If he chooses to Evolve Active Camouflage , Void Assault can be cast three times and Kha'Zix takes reduced damage while in stealth.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3134</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3156</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3072</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1062</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3134</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3156</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3134</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3156</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>