<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>45</id>
  <name>Veigar</name>
  <displayName>Veigar</displayName>
  <title>the Tiny Master of Evil</title>
  <iconPath>Veigar_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Veigar_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>mage,ranged</tags>
  <description>To most, thoughts of yordles do not conjure images to be feared. The easygoing half-pint race, though fierce, is often regarded with some degree of joviality. Their high-pitched voices and naturally cute forms inspire something of a protective instinct in the larger races, or at least bring to mind images of children playing at being adults. Every now and again, however, a yordle turns so bad that even at its small stature it strikes terror into the hearts of others. Veigar is one such twisted yordle. As a master of the magical black arts, as well as a corrupter of cosmic energy, he is one of the most powerful sorcerers on Valoran. As a child, Veigar was a normal yordle with one small exception - he had a deep curiosity for the world beyond Bandle City. The young yordle spent much of his time studying the rest of Valoran, and he jumped at the chance to join a business that traded with other major city-states. Unfortunately for both him and the world, a deal with Noxian trader turned into shady business and went bad; Veigar and his companions were subsequently set up to take the fall. Arrested by the authorities, he was imprisoned within the walls of Noxus for years. Such isolation is very dangerous for yordles - undoubtedly why his cruel jailers did such a thing - and Veigar was slowly driven mad. He eventually escaped, having become a twisted version of his former self. Instead of returning to his people and Bandle City, he sought tutelage from dark wizards across the land. With his demented will focused on one task, he quickly became a dangerous and powerful wizard in his own right. Now he seeks to end all conflict on Valoran by bringing all of the city-states to their knees, regardless of their affiliation. The League of Legends is the perfect tool to help him meet his ends - for now. Who says evil needs to come in a fearsome-looking package?</description>
  <quote />
  <quoteAuthor />
  <range>525</range>
  <moveSpeed>340</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>12.25</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.75</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>250</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>55</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.38</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.12</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.9</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.11</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>355</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>82</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>48.3</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>2.625</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>2</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>10</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>6</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>2</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Use Event Horizon to guarantee success landing Dark Matter.*Veigar is extremely mana-hungry early. Try buying mana regen items to increase the effectiveness of your passive and allow you to cast more Baleful Strikes.*Veigar is very fragile. It is valuable to select at least one summoner spell that can be used defensively.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Dark Matter deals very high damage, but it can be avoided. Pay attention to the sound and visual indicator to be aware of when and where the spell will land.*Event Horizon only stuns units on the edge. If you're inside the spell, you can still move and attack.*Veigar's ultimate deals damage based on your AP as well as his own.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Equilibrium</name>
      <iconPath>Veigar_Entropy.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Veigar's mana regen is increased by 1% for each 1% of mana missing.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Baleful Strike</name>
      <cost>60/65/70/75/80 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>8/7/6/5/4</cooldown>
      <iconPath>VeigarBalefulStrike.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Active: Unleashes dark energy at target enemy, dealing 80/125/170/215/260 (+0.6) magic damage. If the target is killed, Veigar gains 1 Ability Power. This bonus is doubled against Champions, large minions and large monsters. Passive: Veigar gains 1/2/3/4/5 Ability Power when he kills a champion from any source of damage. Ability Power bonus: +</effect>
      <description>Unleashes dark energy at target enemy, dealing magic damage. If a unit is killed, Veigar gains some Ability Power permanently.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Dark Matter</name>
      <cost>70/80/90/100/110 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/10/10/10/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>VeigarDarkMatter.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>After 1.2 seconds, dark matter falls from the sky to the target location, dealing 120/170/220/270/320 (+1) magic damage.</effect>
      <description>Veigar calls a great mass of dark matter to fall from the sky to the target location, dealing magic damage when it lands.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Event Horizon</name>
      <cost>80/90/100/110/120 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>20/19/18/17/16</cooldown>
      <iconPath>VeigarEventHorizon.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Veigar twists the edges of space around the target location for 3 seconds, stunning enemies who pass through the perimeter for 1.5/1.75/2/2.25/2.5 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Veigar twists the edges of space around the target location for 3 seconds, stunning enemies who pass through the perimeter for a short duration.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Primordial Burst</name>
      <cost>125/175/225 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>130/110/90</cooldown>
      <iconPath>VeigarPrimordialBurst.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Blasts an enemy champion, dealing 250/375/500 (+1.2) plus 80% of his target's Ability Power in magic damage.</effect>
      <description>Blasts target enemy champion, dealing a large base amount of magic damage plus 80% of his target's AP.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3128</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3157</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3180</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3028</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3128</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3157</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>