<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>18</id>
  <name>Tristana</name>
  <displayName>Tristana</displayName>
  <title>the Megling Gunner</title>
  <iconPath>Tristana_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Tristana_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>carry,ranged,recommended</tags>
  <description>The Megling Commandos are something of a legend in Bandle City. They have a history that spans centuries, and they remain the oldest yordle military unit still in service. They are renowned for their courage, deadliness, and ruthlessness, making them the most respected and feared of all warriors in Bandle City. Legends of Megling, the valiant founder of the commandos, are still heard throughout Valoran's taverns. It was these legends that most fascinated a young Tristana. Since she was a wee child, Tristana wanted nothing more than to become the crack shot that her idol had been all those years ago. She trained her entire life, until finally she was old enough to join the military and able to earn her place among the Megling Commandos. The senior officers were impressed by her abilities, claiming that Tristana was a natural, and her dream was realized the day she donned her Megling fatigues. Though her heart lies with her unit, the call to the League of Legends was irresistible and now Tristana protects Bandle City as a champion. While intense and focused as a Megling Gunner, Tristana is remarkably different in her personal life. Outside the Fields of Justice, she is friendly and cheerful - the sort of yordle who always has a kind word for everyone. Tristana recently struck up a close friendship with Teemo, the Swift Scout. They are both members of Bandle City's Special Forces, so not only do they bond as yordles, but also as fellow warriors and champions... though she outright ignores any questions pertaining to a blossoming romance.</description>
  <quote>If there's one person I'd trust to take on a difficult mission, it's Tristana - all day long!</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Teemo</quoteAuthor>
  <range>550</range>
  <moveSpeed>325</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>15</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>193</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>32</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.29</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.09</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.02</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.13</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>415</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>82</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>46.5</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>4</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>3</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>3</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>9</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Her massive gun allows Tristana to fire on targets at a great distance. Utilize this to prevent your enemies from ever laying a hand on you.*Use Rocket Jump to leap over an enemy and then use Buster Shot to send them flying back to your allies, but be careful about using this strategy in large team fights.*Using the active ability on Explosive Shot can be useful early game to prevent the other team from healing or using health potions.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*If you see Tristana activate Rapid Fire in a fight, stun her and try to back off until the spell dissipates.*Stand away from your creeps in a lane to take less collateral damage from Explosive Shot.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Draw a Bead</name>
      <iconPath>Tristana_DrawABead.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Increases Tristana's attack range as she levels.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Rapid Fire</name>
      <cost>50/50/50/50/50 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>20/20/20/20/20</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Tristana_headshot.png</iconPath>
      <range>20</range>
      <effect>Increases Tristana's attack speed by 30/45/60/75/90% for 7 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Tristana fires her weapon rapidly, increasing her attack speed for a short time.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Rocket Jump</name>
      <cost>80/80/80/80/80 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>22/20/18/16/14</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Tristana_RendingShot.png</iconPath>
      <range>900</range>
      <effect>Tristana fires at the ground to propel herself to target location, dealing 70/115/160/205/250 (+0.8) magic damage and slowing surrounding units by 60% for 2.5 seconds when she lands. On a champion kill or assist, Rocket Jump's cooldown resets.</effect>
      <description>Tristana fires at the ground to propel herself to a distant location, dealing damage and slowing surrounding units for 3 seconds where she lands.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Explosive Shot</name>
      <cost>50/60/70/80/90 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>16/16/16/16/16</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Tristana_ExplosiveShot.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: Enemies explode when slain by Tristana's basic attacks, dealing 50/75/100/125/150 (+) magic damage to nearby enemies. Active: Rends target enemy, reducing healing and health regeneration by 50% and dealing 110/150/190/230/270 (+1) Magic Damage over 5 seconds.</effect>
      <description>When Tristana kills a unit, her cannonballs burst into shrapnel, dealing damage to surrounding enemies. Can be activated to deal damage to target unit over time, and reduce healing received.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Buster Shot</name>
      <cost>100/100/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>60/60/60</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Tristana_BusterShot.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Tristana fires a massive cannonball at an enemy unit. This deals 300/400/500 (+1.5) magic damage and knocks surrounding units back 600/800/1000 distance.</effect>
      <description>Tristana loads a massive cannonball into her weapon and fires it at an enemy unit. This deals magic damage and knocks the target back.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3126</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1062</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3009</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3185</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3046</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3046</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>