<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>126</id>
  <name>Jayce</name>
  <displayName>Jayce</displayName>
  <title>the Defender of Tomorrow</title>
  <iconPath>Jayce_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Jayce_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,melee,ranged</tags>
  <description>Armed with wit, charm, and his signature transforming hammer, Jayce lives to protect his native Piltover. Long before his nation called him a hero, however, he was a promising young inventor. When Piltover commissioned him to study a rare arcane crystal, Jayce discovered it could be used as a vast energy source. Eager to make a name for himself, he began developing a device to harness its power. Word of the crystal's potential reached beyond the borders of Piltover. Viktor, the machine-augmented scientist from Zaun, brought Jayce an offer - together, they could use the crystal to advance his ''glorious evolution,'' a vision of humanity fused with technology. Jayce refused, but the Zaunite had no intention of leaving empty handed. He effortlessly blasted Jayce aside and seized the crystal, incinerating the lab's meager security force as he left for Zaun. Jayce implored the Piltover government to respond, but the officials refused to support an act of aggression. He decided to act alone, realizing that if no one struck back, Piltover would never be safe. Jayce returned to the lab to prepare for his attack. After intense research, development, and hands-on testing, he emerged with his crowning achievement - the Mercury Hammer. Weapon in hand, Jayce marched to Zaun and began his one-man assault. Viktor's acolytes rushed to stop him, but Jayce smashed them aside, fighting his way into the heart of the lab. Inside, Jayce saw the horrifying brilliance of Viktor's creations, all powered by the energy of the arcane crystal. He realized that his only option was to destroy the power source, but Viktor stood in his way. Though their clash left both scientists heavily wounded, Jayce managed a desperate strike at the crystal. He shattered it and escaped as Viktor's machines erupted in flames. When he returned home, exhausted but victorious, the citizens of Piltover hailed Jayce as a hero. He reveled in the adoration, but knew that his actions had drawn the attention of dangerous enemies. Now devoted to the defense of his people, Jayce is Piltover's best hope for a bright future.</description>
  <quote>Trust me: if we're smart, Piltover can stand strong against any threat. Hey, I'm living proof.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Jayce</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>335</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>12.5</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>240</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>40</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.4</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.14</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.2</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.16</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>420</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>90</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>46.5</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.5</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>6</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>5</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>7</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>6</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Be sure to switch stances often. It will enhance your attacks and grant you quick bursts of speed.*If you find yourself taking lots of damage try using Jayce's Hammer Form as it grants you additional defenses.*Try casting Shock Blast through the Acceleration Gate for increased range and damage.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Jayce can attack in melee or at range. Pay attention to his stance and weapon color to know how he is going to attack.*If you see Jayce drop his Acceleration Gate be careful, he is probably about to cast Shock Blast.*Jayce is strong in the early game. If he gains the advantage play defensively.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130216172601</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Hextech Capacitor</name>
      <iconPath>JayceManOfTomorrow.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Gains 40 Movement Speed for 1.25 seconds and can move through units each time Transform is cast.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>To the Skies! / Shock Blast</name>
      <cost>40/45/50/55/60 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>16/14/12/10/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Jayce_ToTheSkies.png</iconPath>
      <range>600</range>
      <effect>Leaps to an enemy dealing 20/65/110/155/200 (+) physical damage to enemies and slowing them by 30/35/40/45/50% for 2/2/2/2/2 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Hammer Stance: Leaps to an enemy dealing physical damage and slowing enemies. Cannon Stance: Fires an orb of electricity that detonates upon hitting an enemy (or reaching the end of its path) dealing physical damage to all enemies in the area of the explosion.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Lightning Field / Hyper Charge</name>
      <cost>40/40/40/40/40 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/10/10/10/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Jayce_StaticField.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: Gains 6/8/10/12/14 mana per strike while in Hammer Stance. Active: Creates an electric aura dealing 100/170/240/310/380 (+1) magic damage over 4/4/4/4/4 seconds to nearby enemies.</effect>
      <description>Hammer Stance: Passive: Restores mana per strike. Active: Creates a field of lightning damaging nearby enemies for several seconds. Cannon Stance: Gains a burst of energy, increasing attack speed to maximum for several attacks.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Thundering Blow / Acceleration Gate</name>
      <cost>40/50/60/70/80 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>14/13/12/11/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Jayce_ThunderingBlow.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Deals 8/11/14/17/20% of the enemy's maximum health (+) as magic damage and knocks them back a short distance. (200/300/400/500/600 Maximum Damage against monsters)</effect>
      <description>Hammer Stance: Deals magic damage to an enemy and knocks them back a short distance. Cannon Stance: Deploys an Acceleration Gate increasing the movement speed of all allies who pass through it. If Shock Blast is fired through the gate the missile speed, range, and damage will increase.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Mercury Cannon / Mercury Hammer</name>
      <cooldown>6/6/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Jayce_TransformCannon.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Active: Transforms the Mercury Hammer into the Mercury Cannon gaining new abilities and ranged attacks. The next attack in Cannon stance reduces the enemy's Armor and Magic Resist by 10/15/20% for 5/5/5 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Hammer Stance: Transforms the Mercury Hammer into the Mercury Cannon gaining new abilities and increased range. The first attack in this form reduces the target's Armor and Magic Resist. Cannon Stance: Transforms the Mercury Cannon into the Mercury Hammer gaining new abilities and increasing Armor and Magic Resist. The first attack in this form deals additional magic damage.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3057</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3091</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3105</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1062</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3091</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3057</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3057</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3091</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3105</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>