<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>76</id>
  <name>Nidalee</name>
  <displayName>Nidalee</displayName>
  <title>the Bestial Huntress</title>
  <iconPath>Nidalee_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Nidalee_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>support,pusher</tags>
  <description>There are few dwellers, let alone champions, residing in the blasted and dangerous lands that lie south of the Great Barrier. Much of that world still bears the scars of past Runes Wars, especially the mysterious Kumungu Jungle. There are long-forgotten treasures in these strange places which many risk life and limb to acquire. The champion known as Nidalee was only a young girl travelling with her treasure-seeking parents when they lost their way in the dense, rainy jungles. The jungle was unforgiving, and she watched her parents suffer agonizing final days as they fell victim to a mysterious and vicious disease. As improbable as it was for a child to survive in the inhospitable jungle by herself, she did just that. Her youthful innocence and a fortunate naivete caused her to appeal to the beasts of that place and she was taken in by a family of cougars and raised as one of their own. She grew and somehow absorbed the raw magic of the dense wilds, evolving beyond both her human physiology and her feline affectation. On one pivotal day in her life, standing over the torn remnants of a Noxian squad of woodcutters, Nidalee chose to rejoin the so-called civilized world, to fight in the League of Legends so as to protect the vast woods from both Demacia and Noxus. Nidalee was taught to fight by her feline family, battling viciously with tooth and nail. Something in her feline ways may draw you to her, but remember that she is no pussycat.</description>
  <quote />
  <quoteAuthor />
  <range>525</range>
  <moveSpeed>335</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>11</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>220</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>45</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.4</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.1</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.12</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>370</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>90</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>49</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.5</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>4</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>7</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>7</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>5</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Use brush to your advantage! Moving in and out of brush can heavily alter your effectiveness in battle.*In team fights start by harassing with your Javelin Toss, and then switch to cougar form to chase down anyone who flees.*Cougar abilities have no cost associated with them, allowing you to maintain a full stack of Guinsoo's Rageblade for extended periods of time.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Nidalee's traps are difficult to see, but are visible to both teams.*Nidalee's Javelin Toss deals more damage the farther she is. If she is far away, it's imperative to dodge it.*It's difficult to catch a Nidalee pouncing away, so be selective about when to pursue her.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Prowl</name>
      <iconPath>Nidalee_OnTheProwl.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Moving through brush increases Nidalee's Movement Speed by 15% for 2 seconds.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Javelin Toss / Takedown</name>
      <cost>50/60/70/80/90 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>6/6/6/6/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Nidalee_JavelinThrow.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Human: Nidalee tosses her javelin, dealing 55/95/140/185/230 (+0.65) magic damage on impact (deals up to 250% damage the farther away the target is). Cougar: Nidalee's next attack deals additional damage based on how low her opponent's life is.</effect>
      <description>In human form, Nidalee throws a spiked javelin at her target that gains damage as it flies. As a cougar, her next attack will attempt to fatally wound her target, dealing more damage the less life they have.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Bushwhack / Pounce</name>
      <cost>60/75/90/105/120 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>18/18/18/18/18</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Nidalee_Bushwhack.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Human: Nidalee lays a trap that deals 80/125/170/215/260 (+0.4) magic damage over 2 seconds, reveals the target, and reduces their Armor and Magic Resist by 20/25/30/35/40% for 12 seconds. Traps last for 4 minutes. Cougar: Nidalee lunges forward, dealing damage to surrounding enemies.</effect>
      <description>In human form, Nidalee lays a damaging trap for unwary opponents that, when sprung, reveals the target and reduces their Armor and Magic Resist for 12 seconds. As a cougar, she pounces forward, dealing a small amount of damage when she lands. Pounce is not affected by cooldown reduction.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Primal Surge / Swipe</name>
      <cost>60/80/100/120/140 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/10/10/10/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Nidalee_PrimalSurge.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Human: Nidalee heals an allied champion for 50/85/120/155/190 (+0.7) and grants them a 20/30/40/50/60% attack speed for 7 seconds. Cougar: Nidalee claws at enemies in front of her.</effect>
      <description>In human form, Nidalee channels the spirit of the cougar to heal her allies and imbue them with attack speed for a short duration. As a cougar, she rapidly claws enemies in front of her.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Aspect Of The Cougar</name>
      <cooldown>4/4/4</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Nidalee_AspectOfTheCougar.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Human: Nidalee transforms into a vicious cougar, gaining 20/20/20 Movement Speed, and her basic abilities become Takedown, Pounce, and Swipe. Cougar: Nidalee transforms back into human form.</effect>
      <description>Nidalee transforms into a cougar, gaining new abilities and increased Movement Speed.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3124</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1027</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3117</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3124</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3057</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3070</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3001</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3165</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>