<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>57</id>
  <name>Maokai</name>
  <displayName>Maokai</displayName>
  <title>the Twisted Treant</title>
  <iconPath>Maokai_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Maokai_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>tank,pusher,melee</tags>
  <description>The twisting magical energies unleashed by mages during the Rune Wars caused an incredible amount of devastation to the natural world. The League was established to control the use of this magic by confining it to the Fields of Justice. By limiting its use to there, they thought that they could prevent it from doing further harm to the environment. It seemed that they were successful until Maokai came into being. During a League match on The Twisted Treeline, Maokai, an ancient oak that stood above the upper jungle, spontaneously roared to life. Ripped from the natural balance by arcane forces, his sentience was forged in chaos. Before the Adjudicators of the League could step in and suppress him, he slew all six champions participating in the match. The scholars of the Arcanum Majoris took a keen interest in him, as they were eager to discover the secrets of his animation. Maokai was furious, however. He abhorred the existence that was thrust upon him; he felt it was a corruption of nature. He learned to communicate with people in hopes of finding a way to be returned to his former, true state. Seizing the opportunity, the League offered a trade. They would research a way to revert him so long as he agreed to fight in the League of Legends. Maokai was indifferent to verdicts rendered by the League, but he was eager to punish summoners for their wanton use of magic. He agreed to the terms under one condition: once they learned how to turn him back, they would never animate another tree again. He wears a lantern on the Fields of Justice to set him apart from the other trees, and as a warning to the animals that would do him harm.</description>
  <quote>I will use this power until I am free of it.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Maokai</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>335</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>18</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>4</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>250</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>46</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.29</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.09</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.45</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.17</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>421</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>90</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>58</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>8</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>6</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>4</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>3</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Saplings can be tossed into brush or over terrain to gain line of sight on your enemies.*Save Vengeful Maelstrom for after your opponents have fully committed to a fight.*Ranking up Arcane Smash and Twisted Advance gives Maokai powerful crowd control moves, while ranking up Sapling Toss will improve your damage output and ability to farm.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Saplings can be avoided by placing friendly minions between yourself and them. You can also just outrun them if you're fast.*Vengeful Maelstrom does more damage if you attack Maokai or his allies within the area of effect. Stay out of the area to avoid the damage.*Maokai will avoid taking damage while he's using Twisted Advance, so don't waste your spells.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Sap Magic</name>
      <iconPath>Maokai_SapMagic.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Each time a spell is cast near Maokai he draws energy from it, gaining a charge of Magical Sap. When Maokai has 5 charges his next basic attack heals him for 7% of his max HP.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Arcane Smash</name>
      <cost>55/55/55/55/55 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>6/6/6/6/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Maokai_ArcaneSmash.png</iconPath>
      <range>600</range>
      <effect>Maokai releases an arcane shockwave. Nearby enemies are knocked back and all affected enemies take 70/115/160/205/250 (+0.4) magic damage and are slowed by 20/27/34/41/48% for 2 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Maokai knocks back nearby enemies with a shockwave, dealing magic damage and slowing them.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Twisted Advance</name>
      <cost>75/80/85/90/95 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>13/13/13/13/13</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Maokai_TwistedAdvance.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Maokai transforms into a cloud of arcane energy that quickly travels to a target enemy, deals 80/115/150/185/220 (+0.8) magic damage and roots it for 1/1.25/1.5/1.75/2 second(s).</effect>
      <description>Maokai dissolves into a cloud of arcane energies. He regrows near a target enemy, dealing damage and rooting it in place.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Sapling Toss</name>
      <cost>70/80/90/100/110 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>12/12/12/12/12</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Maokai_SaplingToss.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Maokai flings a sapling that deals 40/75/110/145/180 (+0.4) magic damage on impact. The sapling wards the nearby area, and will chase enemies that approach, exploding to deal 80/130/180/230/280 (+) magic damage. Saplings last for 35/35/35/35/35 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Maokai flings a sapling that deals area damage on impact. The sapling then wards the nearby area. When enemies approach, the sapling attacks enemies with an arcane blast.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Vengeful Maelstrom</name>
      <cost>75/75/75 Mana, 30 Mana Per Second</cost>
      <cooldown>40/30/20</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Maokai_VengefulMaelstrom.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Toggle: Maokai creates a magical vortex that protects him and allied champions by reducing damage from non-turret sources by 20/20/20%. Maokai can end the effect to release the stored energy, dealing 100/150/200 (+0.5) (+2 per damage absorbed) magic damage to enemies within the vortex. Maokai can store up to 200/250/300 bonus damage.</effect>
      <description>Maokai shields his allies by drawing power from hostile spells and attacks, reducing non-tower damage done to allied champions in the area. When Maokai ends the effect, he unleashes the absorbed energy to deal damage to enemies within the vortex.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1054</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3027</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3110</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3102</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3010</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3027</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3180</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3096</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3027</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3001</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3110</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3102</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>