<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>37</id>
  <name>Sona</name>
  <displayName>Sona</displayName>
  <title>Maven of the Strings</title>
  <iconPath>Sona_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Sona_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>support,ranged,recommended</tags>
  <description>Sona has no memories of her true parents. As an infant, she was found abandoned on the doorstep of an Ionian adoption house, nestled atop an ancient instrument in an exquisite case of unknown origins. She was an unusually well-behaved child, always quiet and content. Her caretakers were sure she would find a home quickly, but it soon became apparent that what they mistook for uncommon geniality was actually an inability to speak or to produce any sound whatsoever. Sona remained at the adoption house until her teens, watching in hopeless silence as prospective adopters passed her by. During this time, the caretakers sold her unusual instrument to anxious collectors, hoping to build her a trust. For a myriad of bizarre and unexpected reasons, however, it would be returned, or simply appear again outside the house. When a wealthy Demacian woman named Lestara Buvelle learned of the instrument, she immediately embarked to Ionia. When the caretakers showcased the instrument for her, she rose wordlessly and explored the house, stopping outside Sona's room. Without hesitation, Lestara adopted her and left a generous donation for the instrument. With Lestara's guidance, Sona discovered a deep connection with the instrument which Lestara called an 'etwahl'. In her hands, it played tones which stilled or quivered the hearts of those around her. Within months, she was headlining with the mysterious etwahl for sold-out audiences. She played as though plucking heartstrings, effortlessly manipulating the emotions of her listeners - all without a single written note. In secret, she discovered a potent and deadly use for her etwahl, using its vibrations to slice objects from a distance. She honed this discipline in private, mastering her gift. When she felt prepared, she went to the only place which could offer her a fitting recital: the League of Legends.</description>
  <quote>Her melody moves the soul, her silence sunders the body.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Jericho Swain, after attending her concert</quoteAuthor>
  <range>550</range>
  <moveSpeed>330</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>6</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.3</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>265</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>45</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.4</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.13</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.9</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.11</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>340</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>70</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>47</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>2</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>8</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>1</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>5</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Make use of Hymn of Valor's bonus ability power for empowering your next spell.*Save Crescendo for the game-altering moment.*Constantly switching between Song of Celerity and Aria of Perseverance will grant you maximum survivability.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Spread out when you see Sona so she can't make your entire team dance.*Kill Sona first, as she will heal up her team if left alone for too long.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Power Chord</name>
      <iconPath>Sona_PowerChordCharged.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>After casting 3 spells, Sona's next attack deals bonus magic damage in addition to a bonus effect depending on what song Sona is currently playing.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Hymn of Valor</name>
      <cost>45/50/55/60/65 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>7/7/7/7/7</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sona_HymnofValor.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Persistent Aura: Increases the Attack Damage and Ability Power of nearby allied Champions by 4/8/12/16/20. Activation: Deals 50/100/150/200/250 (+0.7) magic damage to the nearest two enemies (prioritizes Champions). Power Chord - Staccato: Deals double power chord damage.</effect>
      <description>Sona plays the Hymn of Valor, granting nearby allied champions bonus Damage and Ability Power. Additionally, casting this ability sends out bolts of sound, dealing magic damage to the nearest two enemy champions or monsters.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Aria of Perseverance</name>
      <cost>60/65/70/75/80 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>7/7/7/7/7</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sona_AriaofPerseverance.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Persistent Aura: Grants nearby allied Champions 3/6/9/12/15 bonus Armor and Magic Resist. Activation: Heals Sona and the most wounded nearby allied Champion for 40/60/80/100/120 (+0.25) and grants 8/11/14/17/20 additional Armor and Magic Resist for 3 seconds. Power Chord - Diminuendo: Reduces an enemy's total damage output by 20% for 4 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Sona plays the Aria of Perseverance, granting nearby allied champions bonus Armor and Magic Resist. Additionally, casting this ability sends out healing melodies, healing Sona and a nearby wounded ally.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Song of Celerity</name>
      <cost>65/65/65/65/65 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>7/7/7/7/7</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sona_SongofDiscord.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Persistent Aura: Grants nearby allied Champions 4/8/12/16/20 bonus Movement Speed. Activation: Grants nearby allied Champions 6/8/10/12/14% Movement Speed for 1.5 seconds. Power Chord - Tempo: Slows an enemy by 40% for 2 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Sona plays the Song of Celerity, granting nearby allied champions bonus Movement Speed. Additionally, casting this ability energizes nearby allies with a burst of speed.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Crescendo</name>
      <cost>100/150/200 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>140/120/100</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Sona_Crescendo.png</iconPath>
      <range>900</range>
      <effect>Strikes an irresistible chord forcing enemy Champions to dance for 1.5 seconds and take 150/250/350 (+0.8) magic damage.</effect>
      <description>Sona plays her ultimate chord, forcing enemy champions to dance and dealing magic damage to them.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1005</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3099</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3003</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1027</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3003</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3180</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3070</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3069</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3110</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>