<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>84</id>
  <name>Akali</name>
  <displayName>Akali</displayName>
  <title>the Fist of Shadow</title>
  <iconPath>Akali_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Akali_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>assassin,melee,stealth</tags>
  <description>There exists an ancient order originating in the Ionian Isles dedicated to the preservation of balance. Order, chaos, light, darkness -- all things must exist in perfect harmony for such is the way of the universe. This order is known as the Kinkou and it employs a triumvirate of shadow warriors to uphold its causes in the world. Akali is one of these shadow warriors, entrusted with the sacred duty of Pruning the Tree - eliminating those who threaten the equilibrium of Valoran. A prodigal martial artist, Akali began training with her mother as soon as she could make a fist. Her mother's discipline was relentless and unforgiving, but predicated on the fundamental principle: ''We do that which must be done.'' When the Kinkou inducted her into the order at the age of fourteen, she could slice a dangling chain with a chop of her hand. There was no question - she would succeed her mother as the Fist of Shadow. She has had to do much in this role which others might find morally questionable, but to her it is in service of her mother's inviolable doctrine. She now works with her fellows Shen and Kennen to enforce the balance of Valoran. This hallowed pursuit has unsurprisingly led the triumvirate to the Fields of Justice.</description>
  <quote>The Fist of Shadow strikes from the cover of death itself. Do not impede the balance.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor />
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>350</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>16.5</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>200</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>0</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>10</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.45</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.13</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>445</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>85</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>53</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.2</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>3</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>8</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>6</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>5</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*You can use runes and masteries to trigger her passive.*Akali excels at killing weaker characters. Let your team initiate and then strike at the people in the back.*Find the balance between storing Essence of Shadows, and using Shadow Dance before having max charges.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Akali can still be hit by area effect spells while invisible inside Twilight Shroud.*Akali greatly benefits from both Mejai's Soulstealer and the Sword of the Occult. Watch which items she gets and prioritize her accordingly.*Return to base if your Health is low and Akali has multiple charges of her ultimate.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Twin Disciplines</name>
      <iconPath>AkaliTwinDisciplines.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Upon obtaining 20 Ability Power, Akali's basic attacks deal 8% bonus magic damage, increasing by 1% for every 6 Ability Power gained thereafter. Upon obtaining 10 Bonus Attack Damage, Akali gains 8% Spell Vamp, increasing by an additional 1% for every 6 Bonus Attack Damage gained thereafter.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Mark of the Assassin</name>
      <cost>60/60/60/60/60 Energy</cost>
      <cooldown>6/5.5/5/4.5/4</cooldown>
      <iconPath>AkaliMota.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Akali throws her kama at a target enemy to deal 35/55/75/95/115 (+0.4) magic damage and mark the target for 6/6/6/6/6 seconds. Akali's melee attacks against a marked target will consume the mark to cause 45/70/95/120/145 (+) magic damage and restore 20/25/30/35/40 Energy.</effect>
      <description>Akali spins her kama at a target enemy to deal magic damage and mark the target for 6 seconds. Akali's melee attacks against a marked target will trigger and consume the mark to cause additional damage and restore Energy.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Twilight Shroud</name>
      <cost>80/75/70/65/60 Energy</cost>
      <cooldown>20/20/20/20/20</cooldown>
      <iconPath>AkaliTwilightShroud.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Akali throws down a cover of smoke that lasts for 8/8/8/8/8 seconds. While inside the area, Akali gains 10/20/30/40/50 Armor and Magic Resist and becomes invisible. Attacking or using abilities will briefly reveal her. Enemies inside the smoke are slowed by 14/18/22/26/30%.</effect>
      <description>Akali throws down a cover of smoke. While inside the area, Akali gains Armor and Magic Resist and becomes invisible. Attacking or using abilities will briefly reveal her. Enemies inside the smoke have their Movement Speed reduced.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Crescent Slash</name>
      <cost>60/55/50/45/40 Energy</cost>
      <cooldown>7/6/5/4/3</cooldown>
      <iconPath>AkaliCrescentSlash.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Akali flourishes her kamas, slicing nearby enemy units for 30/55/80/105/130 (+) (+0.3) physical damage. Triggers Mark of the Assassin on targets affected by it.</effect>
      <description>Akali flourishes her kamas, dealing damage based on her Attack Damage and Ability Power.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Shadow Dance</name>
      <cooldown>2/1.5/1</cooldown>
      <iconPath>AkaliShadowDance.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Akali moves through shadows to quickly strike her target, dealing 100/175/250 (+0.5) magic damage. Akali stores an Essence of Shadow on kills and assists as well as every seconds up to 3/3/3 total.</effect>
      <description>Akali moves through shadows to quickly strike her target, dealing damage and consuming an Essence of Shadow charge. Akali recharges Essence of Shadow charges both periodically and upon kills and assists, max 3 stacks.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1036</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3044</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3124</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3078</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3044</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3124</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1052</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3146</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3057</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>