<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>102</id>
  <name>Shyvana</name>
  <displayName>Shyvana</displayName>
  <title>the Half-Dragon</title>
  <iconPath>Shyvana_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Shyvana_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,melee</tags>
  <description>A half-breed born from the union between dragon and human, Shyvana searched all her life for belonging. Persecution forged her into a brutal warrior, and those who dare stand against Shyvana face the fiery beast lurking just beneath her skin. Dragonkind considered Shyvana's impure blood an abomination, and she spent her youth pursued relentlessly by one cruel drake. Constantly on the run, she and her father, an outcast dragon, never knew a lasting home. A brutal reflection of countless battles, Shyvana grew hateful and savage. After years of strife, her father finally fell to the other dragon, but not before gravely wounding his foe. Furious with grief, Shyvana pursued her father's murderer as he fled north to recover. There she encountered a group of humans on the trail of the same drake. Though the men looked upon her in fear, their leader approached Shyvana peacefully. He introduced himself as Jarvan IV, the Prince of Demacia, and offered to aid Shyvana in her quest for vengeance. Together they hunted down and confronted the vicious dragon that had slain her father. Shyvana did not expect the men to survive, but in the clash of fire and steel, Jarvan and his men fought with strength she had never believed humans to possess. The ironclad warriors drove their foe into submission, and Shyvana struck the final blow, tearing the beast's heart from its body. Inspired by her ferocity, Jarvan offered her a place in the ranks of his elite guard. Shyvana could still see fear in the eyes of his men, but she longed for a true home. Trusting Jarvan's word, she accepted his offer and now serves as a Demacian warrior. Though her human allies admire her power, they keep their distance. Shyvana strives to repay the prince's kindness with the power of the dragon within, but she cannot help but wonder if the humans are right to fear her.</description>
  <quote>I have proven my might to dragonkind - what challenge shall humans pose?</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Shyvana</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>350</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>18</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.35</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>100</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>0</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>0</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.45</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.16</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>435</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>95</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>55</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.4</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>6</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>5</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>4</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>7</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Shyvana's abilities all benefit from attacking units. As a result, Attack Speed items are more valuable on her than most champions.*Flame Breath is great to level-up against difficult lane opponents.*Burnout is an ideal choice for jungling. Monsters will be hit by the full duration, and the speed boost improves her ganking potential.*It can be valuable to purchase one of the items that can slow enemies: Phage, Frozen Mallet, Trinity Force, or Entropy.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*A significant portion of Shyvana's power is generated through aggression, making her weak against opponents who are able to keep their distance.*All of Shyvana's basic abilities hit multiple enemies in dragon form. It's important for opposing champions to not cluster while fighting her.*Shyvana's Fury Bar is an indicator for when her ultimate can be activated. Harassing her when she's low on Fury can be very effective.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Fury of the Dragonborn</name>
      <iconPath>ShyvanaReinforcedScales.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Shyvana's melee attacks enhance her abilities. Twin Bite - Reduces the cooldown by 0.5 seconds. Burnout - Extends the duration by 1 second to a maximum of 6 seconds. Flame Breath - Deals 15% of the ability's damage to debuffed targets. Dragon's Descent - Attacks generate 2 Fury and Shyvana passively gains Fury over time while in human form.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Twin Bite</name>
      <cooldown>10/9/8/7/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>ShyvanaTwinBite.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Shyvana strikes twice on her next attack, dealing (+) physical damage on the second attack. The bonus damage is equal to 80/85/90/95/100% of Shyvana's Attack Damage. Dragon Form: Twin Bite cleaves all units in front Shyvana.</effect>
      <description>Shyvana strikes twice on her next attack. Dragon Form: Twin Bite cleaves all units in front Shyvana.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Burnout</name>
      <cooldown>12/12/12/12/12</cooldown>
      <iconPath>ShyvanaScorchedEarth.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Shyvana deals 25/40/55/70/85 (+) magic damage per second to nearby enemies and moves 30/35/40/45/50% faster for 3 seconds. Shyvana's Movement Speed bonus is reduced over time. Dragon Form: Burnout scorches the earth, continuing to damage enemies that stand on it.</effect>
      <description>Shyvana surrounds herself in fire, dealing magic damage per second to nearby enemies and moving faster for 3 seconds. The movement speed reduces over the duration of the spell. Dragon Form: Burnout scorches the ground beneath it, enemies on the scorched earth continue to take damage.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Flame Breath</name>
      <cooldown>12/11/10/9/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>ShyvanaFlameBreath.png</iconPath>
      <range>925</range>
      <effect>Shyvana unleashes a fireball that deals 80/125/170/215/260 (+0.6) magic damage and burns 15/15/15/15/15% of their Armor for 4 seconds. Dragon Form: Flame Breath engulfs all units in a cone in front of her.</effect>
      <description>Shyvana unleashes a fireball that deals damage to the first enemy it encounters and leaves cinders on the target that reduces their Armor for 4 seconds. Dragon Form: Flame Breath engulfs all units in a cone in front of her.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Dragon's Descent</name>
      <cooldown>0/0/0</cooldown>
      <iconPath>ShyvanaDragonsDescent.png</iconPath>
      <range>1000</range>
      <effect>Active: Shyvana transforms into a dragon and takes flight to a target location. Enemies along her path take 200/300/400 (+0.7) magic damage and are knocked toward her target location. Passive: Shyvana reinforces her scales, increasing her Armor and Magic Resist by 10/15/20. Defensive bonuses are doubled in Dragon Form.</effect>
      <description>Shyvana transforms into a dragon and takes flight to a target location. Enemies along her path take damage and are knocked toward her target location. Shyvana passively gains Armor and Magic Resistance. Defensive bonuses are doubled in Dragon Form.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1054</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3022</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3091</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1062</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3022</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3091</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3022</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3091</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3005</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>