<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>79</id>
  <name>Gragas</name>
  <displayName>Gragas</displayName>
  <title>the Rabble Rouser</title>
  <iconPath>Gragas_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Gragas_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,melee</tags>
  <description>The only thing more important to Gragas than fighting is drinking. His unquenchable thirst for stronger ale has led him in search of the most potent and unconventional ingredients to toss in his still. Impulsive and unpredictable, this rowdy carouser loves cracking kegs as much as cracking heads. Thanks to his strange brews and temperamental nature, drinking with Gragas is always a risky proposition. Gragas has an eternal love of good drink, but his massive constitution prevented him from reaching a divine state of intoxication. One night, when he had drained all the kegs and was left wanting, Gragas was struck by a thought rather than the usual barstool: why couldn't he brew himself something that would finally get him truly drunk? It was then that he vowed to create the ultimate ale. Gragas' quest eventually brought him to the Freljord, where the promise of acquiring the purest arctic water for his recipe led him into uncharted glacial wastes. While lost in an unyielding blizzard, Gragas stumbled upon a great howling abyss. There he found it: a flawless shard of ice unlike anything he had ever seen. Not only did this unmelting shard imbue his lager with incredible properties, but it also had a handy side effect - it kept the mixture chilled at the perfect serving temperature. Under the spell of his new concoction, Gragas headed for civilization, eager to share the fermented fruits of his labor. As fate would have it, the first gathering to catch Gragas' bleary eyes would shape the future of the Freljord. He blundered into a deteriorating negotiation between two tribes discussing an alliance with Ashe. Though Ashe welcomed a break in the tension, the other warriors bristled at the intrusion and hurled insults at the drunken oaf. True to his nature, Gragas replied with a diplomatic headbutt, setting off a brawl matched only in the legends of the Freljord. When the fallen from that great melee finally awoke, Ashe proposed a friendly drink as an alternative to fighting. With their tempers doused in suds, the two tribes, formerly on the brink of war, bonded over a common love of Gragas' brew. Although strife was averted and Gragas hailed a hero, he still had not achieved his dream of drunken blissfulness. So once more, he set off to wander the tundra in search of ingredients for Runeterra's perfect pint.</description>
  <quote>Now this'll put hair on your chest!</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Gragas</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>340</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>16</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.6</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>221</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>47</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.29</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.09</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.45</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.17</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>434</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>89</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>55.78</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.375</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>9</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>6</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>6</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>4</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*The buff from Drunken Rage is applied at the end of the channel, so try to use it before going into fight.*Try to knock enemies back into your towers with Explosive Cask.*Try to combo Body Slam with Explosive Cask to set up kills for your team.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Gragas can knock everybody away with his ultimate. Be careful that you don't get knocked into him or, worse, an enemy tower.*Body Slam is on a very low cooldown, making it difficult to pursue Gragas. Don't overextend yourself chasing him.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Happy Hour</name>
      <iconPath>GragasPassiveHeal.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>On ability use, Gragas takes a drink restoring 2% of his max health over 4 seconds.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Barrel Roll</name>
      <cost>80/90/100/110/120 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>11/10/9/8/7</cooldown>
      <iconPath>GragasBarrelRoll.png</iconPath>
      <range>1200</range>
      <effect>Gragas rolls his cask to a location, which can be activated again to explode or will explode on its own after 5 seconds, dealing 85/135/185/235/285 (+0.9) magic damage and applying a 20/25/30/35/40% attack speed debuff for 3 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Gragas rolls his cask to a location, which can be activated to explode or will explode on its own after 5 seconds. Enemies struck by the blast have their attack speed lowered.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Drunken Rage</name>
      <cooldown>25/25/25/25/25</cooldown>
      <iconPath>GragasDrunkenRage.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect> Gragas guzzles down brew from his cask, channeling for 1 second. He gains 30/45/60/75/90 mana while channeling, and becomes empowered after finishing, increasing physical attack damage by 30/40/50/60/70, and reducing damage taken by 10/12/14/16/18% for 20 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Gragas guzzles down brew from his cask for 1 second, restoring his mana. After finishing, he becomes drunkenly empowered, increasing his damage dealt and reducing damage received.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Body Slam</name>
      <cost>75/75/75/75/75 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>7/7/7/7/7</cooldown>
      <iconPath>GragasBodySlam.png</iconPath>
      <range>600</range>
      <effect>Gragas charges forward, colliding with the first enemy unit he hits, dealing 80/120/160/200/240 (+) (+0.5) magic damage to enemies in the area. Damage is split among targets hit. Units hit by Body Slam are slowed by 35% for 2.5 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Gragas charges to a location and collides with the first enemy unit he comes across, dealing damage to all nearby enemy units and slowing their movement. Damage is split among units hit.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Explosive Cask</name>
      <cost>100/125/150 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>100/90/80</cooldown>
      <iconPath>GragasExplosiveCask.png</iconPath>
      <range>1050</range>
      <effect>Gragas throws his cask to an area. Upon landing, it deals 200/325/450 (+1) magic damage to all units struck, knocking them back.</effect>
      <description>Gragas hurls his cask to a location, which explodes on impact, dealing damage and knocking back enemies caught in the blast radius. </description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3027</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3001</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1063</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3180</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3110</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3027</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3100</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3001</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>