<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>21</id>
  <name>MissFortune</name>
  <displayName>Miss Fortune</displayName>
  <title>the Bounty Hunter</title>
  <iconPath>MissFortune_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>MissFortune_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>ranged,carry</tags>
  <description>For those who brave the harsh seas of Runeterra, attaining one's own ship and crew is the pinnacle of success. Sarah Fortune, a well-respected (some would say legendary) bounty hunter from Bilgewater, was able to achieve this feat just after her sixteenth birthday, etching out her name as the go-to gal for resolving special troubles. No bounty was too difficult or too dangerous for her feminine charm and her renowned use of her twin pistols, ''Shock and Awe''. Her success gave her the means to legitimately purchase her own ship... with a little flirtatious haggling, of course. Things weren't always so fortunate for Miss Fortune, though. When she was young, trade ships began to dot the horizon of her quiet home in the northern shores of Blue Flame Island's largest chunk. Trade routes brought piracy, and the inhabitants soon found themselves caught in a frenzy of pillage. One day, young Sarah returned home to hear gunshots and screaming. Her front door was smashed open; inside, she saw her mother lying in a pool of blood. A sudden blow to her head made her collapse next to her slain mother. The last thing she could remember were her attacker's red eyes, as his face was blocked by a rogue's bandana. Miss Fortune has a strong distrust for pirates and she finds herself constantly bickering with the infamous Gangplank (the only captain to resist her charms) over the direction of Bilgewater politics. Her two goals: to unite the people of Bilgewater, making them into a strong and independent society, and to find the pirate who killed her mother. To that end, she has entered the League of Legends as a champion, trading her skills for the wealth and influence that will help her accomplish both.</description>
  <quote />
  <quoteAuthor />
  <range>550</range>
  <moveSpeed>325</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>15</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>212</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>38</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.39</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.13</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.02</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.13</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>435</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>85</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>46.5</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>2</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>5</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>3</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>8</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Miss Fortune ramps up speed if she isn't attacked by an enemy target. Avoid getting hit to move very fast.*Use Double Up on the furthest enemy minion if enemy champions are hiding in back; it will bounce to them for lots of damage.*Double Up applies On-Hit effects, making items like Frozen Mallet and Bloodthirster very effective.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Miss Fortune's speed boost is removed if she is damaged or debuffed by an enemy.*Miss Fortune is easy to kill if you can reach her; target her first in team fights.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Strut</name>
      <iconPath>MissFortune_Strut.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>After 5 seconds of not being attacked, Miss Fortune gains an additional 25 Movement Speed. This bonus increases by 9 each second up to a maximum bonus of 70.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Double Up</name>
      <cost>70/75/80/85/90 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>9/8/7/6/5</cooldown>
      <iconPath>MissFortune_DoubleUp.png</iconPath>
      <range>650</range>
      <effect>Miss Fortune fires a shot at an enemy target, dealing 25/60/95/130/165 (+) physical damage and 120/120/120/120/120% of that damage to another enemy target behind the first. Applies on-hit effects.</effect>
      <description>Miss Fortune fires a bullet at an enemy, damaging them and a target behind them.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Impure Shots</name>
      <cost>50/50/50/50/50 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>16/16/16/16/16</cooldown>
      <iconPath>MissFortune_ImpureShots.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Passive: Miss Fortune deals 6/8/10/12/14 (+0.05) magic damage to her target with each attack, cumulatively stacking up to 4 times on the same target. Active: Miss Fortune's attack speed is increased by 30/35/40/45/50% for 6 seconds and causes her attacks to lower healing received and health regeneration by the target by 50% for 3 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Miss Fortune passively increases damage dealt to a target with each strike. This ability can be activated to increase Miss Fortune's attack speed and cause her attacks to lower healing received by the target.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Make It Rain</name>
      <cost>80/80/80/80/80 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>15/15/15/15/15</cooldown>
      <iconPath>MissFortune_MakeItRain.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Miss Fortune fires hundreds of bullets into the air that rain down at a location after 0.5 seconds, dealing 90/145/200/255/310 (+0.8) magic damage over 2 seconds and slowing enemies hit by 20/28/36/44/52% for 1 second.</effect>
      <description>Miss Fortune unleashes a flurry of bullets at a location, dealing waves of damage to opponents and slowing them.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Bullet Time</name>
      <cost>100/100/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>120/110/100</cooldown>
      <iconPath>MissFortune_BulletTime.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Miss Fortune channels a barrage of bullets into a cone in front of her for 2 seconds, dealing 65/95/125 (+) (+0.2) physical damage per bullet.</effect>
      <description>Miss Fortune channels a flurry of bullets into a cone in front of her, dealing large amounts of damage to enemies.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3028</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3035</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1062</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3009</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3185</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3046</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1055</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3071</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3031</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3046</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3181</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>