<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>19</id>
  <name>Warwick</name>
  <displayName>Warwick</displayName>
  <title>the Blood Hunter</title>
  <iconPath>Warwick_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Warwick_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,jungler,melee,recommended</tags>
  <description>Warwick was once a man revered for his ability to track down human specimens for the darkest types of scientific research. When his ambitions exceeded his physical limits, he drank a dangerous elixir to transform himself into an unstoppable manhunter. His newfound strength bore a heavy price. Before his transformation, Warwick found his calling in Zaun as a ''procurer'' of human test subjects. Known for his crafty methods and ruthless determination, people regarded him with a cautious mixture of fear and respect. As his reputation grew, so did the demands placed upon him. His clients wanted more rare and dangerous specimens, and they wanted them sooner. To meet their demands, Warwick needed strength that transcended his limited human form. His longtime friend, Singed, devised a powerful formula. The recipe called for three critical components: silver from the Shadow Isles, the fang of a Balefire dire wolf, and the heart of a celestial being. Warwick tracked down the first two in short order, but the third proved a much greater challenge. He traveled to Ionia to trap Soraka, a creature believed to be a child of the stars, but she discovered his ploy and drove him away with powerful magic. Unable to tolerate his failure, Warwick returned to Singed disfigured and furious. He demanded the chemist's incomplete potion, but Singed warned him that the results would be unpredictable. Ignoring his friend's warning, Warwick drank the concoction. The brew transformed him into a creature both man and wolf, infusing him with raw strength and heightened senses. Exhilarated, he immediately began testing his newfound power. Each day his instincts became sharper, but his human half slipped further away. He could feel himself losing control: though he always got his prey, he often failed to bring them back alive. Now he seeks the heart of Soraka to stabilize his transformation before his mind gives way to the feral urges of the beast.</description>
  <quote>Eventually the beast catches up with all of us.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Warwick</quoteAuthor>
  <range>125</range>
  <moveSpeed>345</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>16</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>190</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>30</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.42</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.12</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.41</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.16</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>1.25</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>428</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>98</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>56.76</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.375</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>4</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>4</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>2</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>7</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Warwick is a champion particularly well-suited for killing monsters in the forest. Hungering Strike can sustain your health, especially if you are able to get the Ancient Golem's blue buff.*Warwick's ultimate can stack on-hit effects such as the Black Cleaver or Wit's End.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Warwick is a very strong jungler. Clairvoyance can help you keep track of his position and enable ganks.*Warwick is a very strong 1v1 champion, especially late in the game, so stick with your teammates to make him less effective.*Warwick can solo the dragon on Summoner's Rift early, so try to prevent him from killing it throughout the game.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Eternal Thirst</name>
      <iconPath>Warwick_InnerHunger.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Each of Warwick's attacks will heal him. Each successive attack against the same target will steal more and more Health.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Hungering Strike</name>
      <cost>70/80/90/100/110 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/9/8/7/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Wolfman_SeverArmor.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Strikes an enemy for the greater value between 75/125/175/225/275 (+1) and 8/10/12/14/16% (+1) of the target's maximum Health as magic damage (can only do flat damage to monsters), and heals Warwick for 80/80/80/80/80% of the damage dealt.</effect>
      <description>Takes a bite out of an enemy unit and heals Warwick.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Hunters Call</name>
      <cost>35/35/35/35/35 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>24/22/20/18/16</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Wolfman_FrenziedStrikes.png</iconPath>
      <range>1250</range>
      <effect>Warwick lets out a howl that inspires all nearby allied champions, increasing Warwick's Attack Speed by 40/50/60/70/80% and all nearby friendly champions' Attack Speed by half of that for 10/10/10/10/10 seconds.</effect>
      <description>Warwick lets out a howl, increasing all nearby friendly champions' Attack Speed for a short time.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Blood Scent</name>
      <cooldown>0.5/0.5/0.5/0.5/0.5</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Wolfman_Bloodscent.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Toggle: Warwick senses enemy champions under 50% Health within 1500/2300/3100/3900/4700 distance of him; while he detects a low-health enemy, he gains 20/25/30/35/40% Movement Speed.</effect>
      <description>Warwick passively senses weakened enemy champions around him. The scent of blood sends him into a fury, causing him to move at incredible speeds.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Infinite Duress</name>
      <cost>100/125/150 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>90/80/70</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Wolfman_InfiniteDuress.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Warwick lunges at an enemy champion and supresses them for 1.8/1.8/1.8 seconds. During this time, Warwick attacks his victim 5/5/5 times, dealing a total of 250/335/420 (+) magic damage (triggers on-hit effects 5/5/5 times). Warwick gains 30/30/30% Life Steal for the duration.</effect>
      <description>Warwick lunges at an enemy champion, suppressing his target and dealing magic damage for a few seconds.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1054</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3006</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3126</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3065</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3026</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3065</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3142</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3143</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3111</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3091</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3022</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3068</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3186</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>