<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>7</id>
  <name>Leblanc</name>
  <displayName>LeBlanc</displayName>
  <title>the Deceiver</title>
  <iconPath>Leblanc_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Leblanc_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>assassin,mage,ranged</tags>
  <description>Every city has its dark side, even one whose reputation is already of a questionable hue. Noxus - though its name is already invoked with a mixture of reverence and revulsion - is no exception to this simple truth. Deep within the winding dungeons that honeycomb the earth beneath its dark, meandering streets lies the real underbelly of this sprawling metropolis, a haven for all manner of malevolence. Amongst the cults, covens, and secret societies that call this labyrinth their home, LeBlanc, the Deceiver, presides over the Black Rose, a remnant from a lost, yet similarly unscrupulous time in Noxian history. Ruthless and seemingly ageless, LeBlanc and her ilk were a mainstay in Noxian political affairs during the era before the militarization of the Noxian government. In those days, this guild of powerful magicians met in secret to further their hidden agenda, and to hone a craft more subtle than that preferred by those currently in power. While their exact motives have always remained mysterious, it was widely believed that the Black Rose was the true power behind the throne while the aristocracy still reigned in Noxus. When raw martial prowess became the ultimate determination of whose will held sway in the Empire, the Black Rose seemed to vanish overnight. Many believed that perhaps their time had simply passed, and that its members had put aside their quests for social and political dominance. When LeBlanc reemerged at the gates of the Institute of War, however, it became clear that these masters of shadow and flame had simply been biding their time, waiting for a new global authority to emerge: the League of Legends.</description>
  <quote>The world is very different for those who cannot see beyond what is placed before their very eyes.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>LeBlanc, the Deceiver</quoteAuthor>
  <range>525</range>
  <moveSpeed>335</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>12</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>250</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>50</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.38</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.12</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.9</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.11</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>390</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>75</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>51</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.1</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>4</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>10</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>9</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>1</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*The damage of a mimicked ability is based off the rank of the basic ability. It is important to consider the utility of the spell versus its damage output.*Using Distortion can help your positioning to land Ethereal Chains.*You can chain Sigil of Silence and Ethereal Chains to prevent characters with blink from escaping for up to 4 seconds.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Stunning or silencing LeBlanc will prevent her from activating the return part of Distortion.*Stay behind minions to make Ethereal Chains difficult to land and force her to use Distortion in a suboptimal manner.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130216172601</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Mirror Image</name>
      <iconPath>LeblancMirrorImage.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>When LeBlanc drops below 40% Health, she becomes invisible for 0.5 seconds. When the invisibility fades, she creates a Mirror Image that deals no damage and lasts for up to 8 seconds. Mirror Image has a 1 minute cooldown. Mirror Image can be controlled by holding the Alt key and using the right mouse button. </description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Sigil of Silence</name>
      <cost>70/75/80/85/90 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>6/6/6/6/6</cooldown>
      <iconPath>LeblancMarkOfSilence.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>LeBlanc projects an orb towards her target, dealing 70/110/150/190/230 (+0.6) magic damage and marking the target for 3.5 seconds. If the target takes damage from one of LeBlanc's abilities, the mark will trigger, dealing 20/40/60/80/100 (+) magic damage and silencing the target for 2 seconds.</effect>
      <description>LeBlanc projects an orb towards her target, dealing magic damage and marking the target for 3.5 seconds. If the target takes damage from one of LeBlanc's abilities, the sigil will trigger, dealing damage and silencing the target.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Distortion</name>
      <cost>80/85/90/95/100 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>18/16/14/12/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>LeblancDisplacement.png</iconPath>
      <range>600</range>
      <effect>LeBlanc rapidly moves to a target location, dealing 85/125/165/205/245 (+0.6) magic damage to nearby units. In the following 3 seconds, she can activate Distortion again to return to her starting location.</effect>
      <description>LeBlanc rapidly moves to a target location, dealing magic damage to nearby units. In the following 3 seconds, she can activate Distortion again to return to her starting location.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Ethereal Chains</name>
      <cost>80/80/80/80/80 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/10/10/10/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>LeblancConjureChains.png</iconPath>
      <range>925</range>
      <effect>LeBlanc flings illusionary chains towards a target location. If it hits an enemy unit, it will deal 40/65/90/115/140 (+0.5) initial magic damage and slow their movement speed by 25%. If the target remains shackled for 2 seconds, the target takes an additional 40/65/90/115/140 (+0.5) magic damage and is unable to move for 1/1.3/1.6/1.9/2.2 second(s).</effect>
      <description>LeBlanc flings illusionary chains towards a target location. If it hits an enemy unit, it will deal initial magic damage and slow their movement speed by 25%. If the target remains shackled for 2 seconds, the target takes additional magic damage and is unable to move.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Mimic</name>
      <cost>100/50/0 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>40/32/24</cooldown>
      <iconPath>LeblancMimic.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>LeBlanc can cast the previous spell she cast. The mimicked spell deals 10/25/40% increased damage.</effect>
      <description>LeBlanc can cast a more potent version of the previous spell she cast.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3136</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3102</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3136</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3098</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3136</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3128</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3135</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>