<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>43</id>
  <name>Karma</name>
  <displayName>Karma</displayName>
  <title>the Enlightened One</title>
  <iconPath>Karma_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Karma_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>support,ranged,mage</tags>
  <description>Karma is a woman of indomitable will and unbound spiritual power. She is the soul of Ionia made manifest and an inspiring presence on the battlefield, shielding her allies and turning back her foes. A strong leader torn between tradition and revolution, Karma seeks to protect the peace of Ionia - by force if necessary. Karma once lived a tranquil life in a small Ionian village. Led by elder monks, the villagers practiced a tradition of benevolent magic and pacifism. Known for her powerful connection to the spiritual realm and beloved as a just mediator amongst her people, Karma embraced these traditions as an essential aspect of the enlightenment sought by all Ionians. Her inner peace was tested when the armies of Noxus invaded Ionia. While the village's elder monks insisted their peaceful ways would spare them from violence, Karma had heard enough tales of Noxian cruelty to openly question the elders' wisdom. Stern and unmoving, they told her to trust in tradition. When the invaders marched on the village, the elder monks rode out to negotiate a bloodless end to the battle. The Noxian general was offended by their show of weakness and slaughtered the monks himself as he ordered his soldiers to strike the village. As the Noxians advanced, the villagers prepared to accept death, bound to their peaceful vows. But Karma would not accept death and instead saw another way: sacrificing a single life to spare many others. To save her people, she drew upon the power within and summoned the full force of her will. A burst of spirit fire emerged from her body and spiraled towards the Noxian general. The flame took the form of twin dragons, the symbol of Ionia itself. It was the first time Karma had ever used her powers to harm instead of protect, and neither she nor the villagers had ever seen anything like it. When the magic subsided, the general had fallen before her and his soldiers had scattered. The opposing forces surrendered to Karma's strength leaving her people, and their traditions, untouched. While the war raged on, Karma became a formidable leader of the Ionian resistance, but the conflict did not end when Noxus's armies fled the Ionian shores. Ionia became divided between the resistance fighters who craved vengeance and the monks who demanded a return to spiritual tradition. Karma saw a third path, one that combined the strength Ionia found in war with the peaceful traditions the nation still held dear. She now seeks to return her ravaged land to an enduring peace.</description>
  <quote>Your spirit is something no one can take from you. Use it wisely.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Karma</quoteAuthor>
  <range>525</range>
  <moveSpeed>335</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>10</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.8</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>290</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>50</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>1.36</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0.13</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>0.94</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.11</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>383</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>83</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>50</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3.3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>7</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>8</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>8</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>1</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Gathering Fire rewards aggressive play. Look to land abilities and basic attacks on your opponent to lower Mantra's cooldown and stay on the offensive.*When using Focused Resolve, slow your opponents with Inner Flame or speed yourself up with Inspire if you're having trouble sticking to a target. *Don't be too conservative with Mantra. Gathering Fire is strongest in teamfights, making it easy to recharge Mantra multiple times.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Karma's passive lowers her Mantra cooldown when she hits enemy champions with abilities and basic attacks. Deny her from getting free hits on you.*Karma's Soulflare erupts for bonus damage in the area in which it's placed. React quickly and escape the circle to avoid taking heavy damage.*Focused Resolve is a strong disengage tool. Create distance to avoid being rooted and seek to engage afterwards.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Gathering Fire</name>
      <iconPath>Karma_Passive.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Reduces Mantra's cooldown each time Karma damages an enemy champion with one of her abilities (Half-effect for Karma's basic attacks)</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Inner Flame</name>
      <cost>50/60/70/80/90/0 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>7/6.5/6/5.5/5/10</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Karma_Q1.png</iconPath>
      <range>950</range>
      <effect>Fires a blast of energy that explodes upon enemy contact, dealing 80/125/170/215/260/ (+0.6) magic damage to enemies in the area and slowing their Movement Speed by 25/25/25/25/25/% for 1.5 seconds. Mantra Bonus - Soulflare: Deals (+) additional magic damage and leaves a circle of flame at the impact area or upon reaching maximum range, slowing enemies for 50%. After 1.5 seconds the circle erupts, dealing (+0.6) magic damage to enemies in the area.</effect>
      <description>Karma sends forth a ball of spirit energy that explodes and deals damage upon hitting an enemy unit. Mantra Bonus: In addition to the explosion, Mantra increases the destructive power of her Inner Flame, creating a cataclysm which deals damage after a short delay.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Focused Resolve</name>
      <cost>70/75/80/85/90/0 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>16/15/14/13/12/13.5</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Karma_W1.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Links Karma to target enemy champion, revealing them, and dealing 60/110/160/210/260/ (+0.6) magic damage over 2 seconds, rooting them in place for 1/1.25/1.5/1.75/2/ seconds if the link is not broken. Mantra Bonus - Renewal: Focused Resolve deals (+0.6) bonus magic damage and heals Karma over the duration for 25% (+%) of her missing Health.</effect>
      <description>Karma creates a tether between herself and a targeted enemy, dealing damage over time and revealing them. If the tether is not broken, the enemy will be rooted. Mantra Bonus: Karma strengthens the link, dealing bonus damage and healing.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Inspire</name>
      <cost>60/70/80/90/100/110 Mana</cost>
      <cooldown>10/10/10/10/10/8</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Karma_E1.png</iconPath>
      <range>800</range>
      <effect>Target ally gains a shield, granting 40/45/50/55/60/% Movement Speed for 1.5/1.5/1.5/1.5/1.5/ seconds and absorbing 80/120/160/200/240/ (+0.5) damage for 4/4/4/4/4/ seconds. Mantra Bonus - Defiance: The shield overflows with energy, dealing (+) magic damage to enemy units around her target. Allied champions around her target gain half that amount as a shield, and are also hasted by 60/60/60/60/60/%.</effect>
      <description>Karma summons a protective shield that absorbs incoming damage and increases the movement speed of the protected ally. Mantra Bonus: In addition to casting the shield, energy radiates out from the shield, dealing damage to enemies and applying Inspire to allied champions.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Mantra</name>
      <cooldown>45</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Karma_R.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Karma empowers her next ability within 8 seconds for an additional effect. Soulflare: Deals bonus magic damage and leaves behind a circle of flame, heavily slowing enemies and dealing damage after a brief delay. Renewal: The link deals bonus magic damage to her target, healing Karma for 25% of her missing Health while the two are linked. Defiance: Allied champions around Karma's target become shielded and gain Movement Speed; Enemy units around her target are dealt magic damage.</effect>
      <description>Karma empowers her next ability to do an additional effect. Mantra is available at level 1 and does not require a skill point.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1056</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3110</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3105</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3152</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3010</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3027</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3110</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3152</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3098</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3158</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3165</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3110</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3152</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>