<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Champion xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <id>8</id>
  <name>Vladimir</name>
  <displayName>Vladimir</displayName>
  <title>the Crimson Reaper</title>
  <iconPath>Vladimir_Square_0.png</iconPath>
  <portraitPath>Vladimir_0.jpg</portraitPath>
  <tags>fighter,mage,ranged</tags>
  <description>There is a temple hidden in the mountains between Noxus and the Tempest Flats, where the secrets of an ancient and terrifying sorcery are kept. The area surrounding the temple is littered with the exsanguinated corpses of those who have mistakenly wandered too close. These served only to pique the curiosity of Vladimir, when - in his youth - he trekked through these mountains during his flight from Noxus. A day earlier, the teenaged Vladimir had brutally murdered two boys his age, for no better reason than to enjoy the intoxicating scarlet bloom that surged forth. He realized immediately that he would never be able to suppress his murderous desires, and if he remained in Noxus, his foul deeds were sure to catch up with him. Without hesitation, he abandoned the city-state, and journeyed south. The trail of bodies led him to a crumbling stone temple. Inside he found an aging monk who appraised him with eyes of pure crimson. Vladimir surprised the monk by returning the wicked gaze with zeal. Recognizing the boy's sinister craving, the monk taught Vladimir how to manipulate and control the fluid of life, often practicing on passing travelers. When it came time for Vladimir to learn the final lesson, the monk warned that failure would result in death. Vladimir did not fail, but success bore a grisly surprise. During the ritual, every drop of the monk's blood was drawn from his body and fused with Vladimir's, imbuing him with his master's magical essence, and that of every hemomancer before him. Left alone and suddenly without purpose, Vladimir resolved to return to Noxus, demanding enrollment in the League to prove the supremacy of his craft. When the Noxian High Command observed the gruesome fates which befell the palace guards, they elected to avail themselves of Vladimir's unsavory talents.</description>
  <quote>That which runs through you will run you through.</quote>
  <quoteAuthor>Vladimir</quoteAuthor>
  <range>450</range>
  <moveSpeed>335</moveSpeed>
  <armorBase>12</armorBase>
  <armorLevel>3.5</armorLevel>
  <manaBase>0</manaBase>
  <manaLevel>0</manaLevel>
  <criticalChanceBase>0</criticalChanceBase>
  <criticalChanceLevel>0</criticalChanceLevel>
  <manaRegenBase>0</manaRegenBase>
  <manaRegenLevel>0</manaRegenLevel>
  <healthRegenBase>1.2</healthRegenBase>
  <healthRegenLevel>0.12</healthRegenLevel>
  <magicResistBase>30</magicResistBase>
  <magicResistLevel>0</magicResistLevel>
  <healthBase>400</healthBase>
  <healthLevel>85</healthLevel>
  <attackBase>45</attackBase>
  <attackLevel>3</attackLevel>
  <ratingDefense>6</ratingDefense>
  <ratingMagic>8</ratingMagic>
  <ratingDifficulty>2</ratingDifficulty>
  <ratingAttack>2</ratingAttack>
  <tips>*Transfusion instantly deals damage to the enemy before healing Vladimir, making it one of the best last hitting tools in the game.*Cast Hemoplague where it will afflict the most units.*Sanguine Pool pops incoming missiles, so it can be used to dodge disables.</tips>
  <opponentTips>*Be wary of team fights while afflicted by Vladimir's Hemoplague.*Making Vladimir use Sanguine Pool at the start of a fight will maximize the health cost of the ability to him.*Items that counter health stacking, such as Deathfire Grasp and Madred's Bloodrazor, are very effective against Vladimir.</opponentTips>
  <date>20130430192454</date>
  <abilities>
    <Ability>
      <rank>1</rank>
      <name>Crimson Pact</name>
      <iconPath>Vladimir_BloodGorged.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <description>Every 40 points of bonus health gives Vladimir 1 ability power and every 1 point of ability power gives Vladimir 1.4 bonus health (does not stack with itself).</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>2</rank>
      <name>Transfusion</name>
      <cooldown>10/8.5/7/5.5/4</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Vladimir_Transfusion.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Vladimir drains the lifeforce of his target, dealing 90/125/160/195/230 (+0.6) magic damage and healing himself for 15/25/35/45/55 (+).</effect>
      <description>Vladimir drains life from his target.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>3</rank>
      <name>Sanguine Pool</name>
      <cost>20/20/20/20/20 % of Current Health</cost>
      <cooldown>26/23/20/17/14</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Vladimir_SanguinePool.png</iconPath>
      <range>350</range>
      <effect>Vladimir sinks into a pool of blood for 2 seconds, becoming untargetable and slowing enemies above him by 40%. Vladimir deals 80/135/190/245/300 (+ [15% of bonus Health]) magic damage over the duration and heals himself for 12.5% of that amount.</effect>
      <description>Vladimir sinks into a pool of blood becoming untargetable for 2 seconds. Additionally, enemies on the pool are slowed and Vladimir siphons life from them.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>4</rank>
      <name>Tides of Blood</name>
      <cost>0/40/50/60/70 Health</cost>
      <cooldown>4.5/4.5/4.5/4.5/4.5</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Vladimir_TidesofBlood.png</iconPath>
      <range>610</range>
      <effect>Vladimir unleashes a torrent of blood, dealing 60/85/110/135/160 (+0.45) magic damage to nearby enemies. Each cast gives him an Empowered stack (max 4), increasing his healing and regeneration by 4/5/6/7/8% each. Additionally, Tides of Blood cost and damage increases by 25% per stack.</effect>
      <description>Vladimir unleashes a torrent of blood, damaging surrounding enemies. Additionally, multiple Tides of Blood in a short period of time cause them to cost additional health and deal additional damage, and increases his healing and regeneration by 8%.</description>
    </Ability>
    <Ability>
      <rank>5</rank>
      <name>Hemoplague</name>
      <cooldown>150/135/120</cooldown>
      <iconPath>Vladimir_Hemoplague.png</iconPath>
      <range>0</range>
      <effect>Vladimir infects the target area with a virulent plague, causing 12/12/12% increased damage for 5 seconds. After 5 seconds, infected enemies take 150/250/350 (+0.7) magic damage.</effect>
      <description>Vladimir infects an area with a virulent plague. Affected enemies take increased damage for the duration. Hemoplague deals additional magic damage after a few seconds to infected enemies.</description>
    </Ability>
  </abilities>
  <setitems>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1007</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3136</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3157</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>CLASSIC</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>1028</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3136</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3001</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3090</itemId>
      <gameMode>DOMINION</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3145</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3020</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3136</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3116</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3157</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
    <SetItem>
      <itemId>3089</itemId>
      <gameMode>ARAM</gameMode>
    </SetItem>
  </setitems>
</Champion>